<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wta on Stats On the T</title>
    <link>https://skoval.github.io/categories/wta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wta on Stats On the T</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://skoval.github.io/categories/wta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Serena Williams Isn&#39;t the 700th Player By Any Measure</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/06/27/serena-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/06/27/serena-defense/</guid>
      <description>While tennis&amp;rsquo; top players have been spending this week making their final preparations for the upcoming 2017 Wimbledon Championships, one tennis commentator has been stirring up controversy. In a recent interview with NPR, 7-time Grand Slam champion John McEnroe inexplicably took a shot at 23-time Major winner Serena Williams when he opined that she would be ranked only 700&amp;mdash; a Futures-level player&amp;mdash;if she played on the men&amp;rsquo;s tour.
McEnroe&amp;rsquo;s comments continue a string of headline-grabbing chauvinistic behavior among some of the sport&amp;rsquo;s most well-known retired players that includes Ilie Nastase and Roger Moore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2017 WTA Season Looking A Lot Like Early 2003</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/06/18/wta-elo-epochs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/06/18/wta-elo-epochs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the major tennis storylines of 2017 has been the opening up of the field on the WTA tour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a number of former dominant players, like Serena Williams and Victoria Azarenka, out of the game and others, like Maria Sharapova and Petra Kvitova, still early in their return, 2017 has presented a massive opportunity to the tour&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;rising stars. Out of 13 Premier and Grand Slam events completed this season, 10 different women have taken the title win. This has given tennis fans many possible picks for who will emerge as the next major threat on the WTA tour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>French Open WTA Leaders</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/06/10/french-open-wta-leaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/06/10/french-open-wta-leaders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are just hours away from the women&amp;rsquo;s final at the 2017 French Open. After 126 matches, 25 year-old Simona Halep and 20 year-old Jelena Ostapenko are the last women&amp;rsquo;s players remaining. And, whatever the outcome on Saturday in Paris, the women&amp;rsquo;s tour will see a new French Open champion and new Grand Slam title-holder crowned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Women&#39;s French Open Seedings</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/06/03/womens-seeds-french-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/06/03/womens-seeds-french-open/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It only took a few days of main draw play for the 2017 French Open to give fodder to debates on the unpredictability of this year&amp;rsquo;s women&amp;rsquo;s tour. After two rounds, just 9 of the 32 seeds survived to the round of 32, 23 fewer than expected. Those numbers caused &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tennis.com/pro-game/2017/06/tennis-channel-roland-garros-2017-wta-player-draft-update-french-open/66477/&#34;&gt;tennis.com&lt;/a&gt; to conclude that the women&amp;rsquo;s draw was &amp;ldquo;decimated&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>