<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stats On the T</title>
    <link>https://skoval.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Stats On the T</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://skoval.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Did Competition Load Help Make Medvedev a Grand Slam Champion?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2021/09/12/Did-Competition-Load-Help-Medvedev/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2021/09/12/Did-Competition-Load-Help-Medvedev/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Daniil Medvedev may not have gotten the result he wanted at his latest Major opportunity in Melbourne. But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t change the fact that he remains the most successful male player of his generation and the only non-Big-Four player among the current ATP top 10 to have a Grand Slam title. In this post, I look at the extent to which &lt;em&gt;competition load&lt;/em&gt; played a role in getting Medvedev to what has so far been the milestone of his tennis career.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winning the Fantasy Game</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2021/09/12/Fantasy-Tennis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2021/09/12/Fantasy-Tennis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The US Open introduced an extra way to engage with the event this year with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://games.usopen.org/roster&#34;&gt;Fantasy Tennis&lt;/a&gt; competition.  In this post, I share a simulation model that can help with fantasy strategizing. The basic idea is to run outcomes of the US Open men&amp;rsquo;s and women&amp;rsquo;s draws, predict match statistics for each hypothetical match, and tabulate the corresponding fantasy points that are up for grabs with each match. This model alone won&amp;rsquo;t win you the fantasy game, where so much luck is involved, but it can be a useful tool for choosing more winnable strategies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Consistency Win Slams?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2021/08/17/Consistency-Slams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2021/08/17/Consistency-Slams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With 7 consecutive match wins standing between a pro player and a Grand Slam title, it would seem obvious that consistency in performance is essential to a major win. But no player can play to their best in every match. And no player can avoid the occasional off day. This raises a more interesting question with a less obvious answer: what &lt;em&gt;level&lt;/em&gt; of consistency must a player maintain to win a slam?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Clay Ratings Gap is Narrowing</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2021/05/22/Ratings-Gap-Narrowing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2021/05/22/Ratings-Gap-Narrowing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In just one week, Rafael Nadal will begin his journey towards a 14th Roland Garros title. Since his first win in Paris in 2005, Nadal has dominated the surface and only injury has been a consistent foe. Will 2021 continue that pattern? This post looks at the trends in player clay ratings ahead of the French Open main draw and the story they tell about a growing threat to Nadal&amp;rsquo;s reign as the definitive &amp;lsquo;King of Clay&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Stat for Change of Direction</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2021/05/16/Change-of-Direction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2021/05/16/Change-of-Direction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Change of direction&lt;/i&gt; is the skill of moving the ball from one side of the court to the other. Being able to control the direction of the ball during a tennis point can be a key strategy for forcing an opponent out of a comfortable position and setting up a winning shot. With modern tracking data, where the trajectory of every shot in a point is known, we can begin to investigate how change of direction is best quantified. This post is a collection of some initial ideas on a statistic for change of direction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Spatial Exploration of Serve Patterns</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2021/05/02/Spatial-Exploration-Serves/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2021/05/02/Spatial-Exploration-Serves/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using a recently discovered source of summary tracking data for Grand Slam matches, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ptea_test?s=20&#34;&gt;Peter Tea&lt;/a&gt; explores the spatial features of top men&amp;rsquo;s and women&amp;rsquo;s serves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Return Impact Head-to-Heads</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2021/04/17/Return-Impact-H2H/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2021/04/17/Return-Impact-H2H/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Head-to-heads are one of the most fascinating aspects of tennis. While it&amp;rsquo;s easy to look up who is ahead on one record or another, there are still many fundamental patterns of play that we can&amp;rsquo;t easily compare across players. This post goes a small (but I hope interesting) way towards remedying that by introducing a head-to-head visualization tool for comparing the return impact patterns of ATP players.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Search for Surprisingly Sparse Head-to-Heads</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2021/03/14/Sparse-Head-to-Heads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2021/03/14/Sparse-Head-to-Heads/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Small sample size is typical of head-to-heads in pro tennis. Both seeding and knockout tournament designs mean that many pro players have played each other no more than a handful of times or sometimes never at all. Still, I find myself frequently surprised when I come across sparse head-to-heads between some seasoned players. It got me thinking if that reaction is even reasonable and how you might quantify how much some matchups are &lt;i&gt;overdue&lt;/i&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have Matches Become Harder to Predict in the Time of Covid?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2021/03/06/Unpredictable-Pandemic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2021/03/06/Unpredictable-Pandemic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The pandemic has caused the most sustained disruption to the tennis calendar the sport has ever faced. And, while tennis has returned in some form over the past six months, it has not been a return to normal. With all of the challenges players and events have undergone, many of us are likely wondering whether pro competition has changed in some fundamental way? In this post, I try to shed light on this question by looking at trends in event predictability before and during the pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hardcourt First Return Impact Styles</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2021/01/23/Hardcourt-Return-Impact-Styles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2021/01/23/Hardcourt-Return-Impact-Styles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once we can measure player impact patterns on the return, it is natural to use these patterns to compare players. This post delves into these comparisons and presents a set of distinct impact types that describe the impact styles of top ATP players when returning the first serve on hardcourts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Return Impact Maps</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2021/01/19/Return-Impact-Maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2021/01/19/Return-Impact-Maps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Which of the top ATP players are the most aggressive on the serve return? Which are the most defensive? Is Andrey Rublev&amp;rsquo;s serve return style closer to Roger Federer&amp;rsquo;s or Novak Djokovic&amp;rsquo;s? In this post, I introduce an interactive visualization tool to help answer these and many other questions about the return impact of top men&amp;rsquo;s tennis players.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Foray Into Return Impact Patterns</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2020/11/28/return-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2020/11/28/return-impact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The serve return is the most important shot for a receiver.  What can receivers do to put themselves in a better position to make a good impact on the serve return? The answer to that question is too big a task for one blog post alone. As a small first step, I take a look at a new public data source that includes the position of players at the time of return impact in ATP matches. Through a handful of case studies, it delves into the kind of patterns in return positioning these data could help reveal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a Model of Player Availability Can Tell Us About Probable Injuries in Tennis</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2020/11/03/schedule-hmm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2020/11/03/schedule-hmm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2020 tennis calendar was put into a tailspin by the pandemic. In a normal year, a player&amp;rsquo;s competitive schedule can tell us a lot about a player&amp;rsquo;s overall readiness to play, what I will call a player&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;availability&amp;rsquo;. In this post, I show how a Hidden Markov Model can be used to describe a player&amp;rsquo;s competitive schedule as the output from periods of varying availability and how irregularities in availability can be a tell-tale sign of probable injury.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sizing Up the Height Advantage on Serve</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2020/10/25/sizing-up-height-advantage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2020/10/25/sizing-up-height-advantage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can you ever have &lt;em&gt;too much&lt;/em&gt; height in tennis? In this post, &lt;strong&gt;Peter Tea&lt;/strong&gt; analyzes two sides of the &amp;ldquo;big server&amp;rdquo; equation as he delves into the influence of height on the rate of aces hit and aces allowed among ATP players.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Was Djokovic&#39;s Drop Shot Strategy at the French Open a Mistake?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2020/10/18/djokovic-drop-shots/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2020/10/18/djokovic-drop-shots/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The tennis world has now had a week to process the end of the 2020 French Open, but many of us are probably still struggling to understand how the 56th meeting of Novak Djokovic and Rafael Nadal could turn out to be so underwhelming. As one of the most noticeable changes in Djokovic&amp;rsquo;s game strategy this year, it is tempting to point blame at the &lt;em&gt;drop shot&lt;/em&gt;. But would that be a fair assessment? Using data from the Match Charting Project, let&amp;rsquo;s see if we can determine if Djokovic&amp;rsquo;s drop shot strategy was what cost him his latest chance at an 18th Major title.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who&#39;s Got the Power? - Classifying Speed Styles on Serve</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2020/10/10/serve-power-styles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2020/10/10/serve-power-styles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent data feature on the ATP website gives us insight into the average speeds of shots at more top events than just the Grand Slams. What can these speed stats tell us about a player&amp;rsquo;s style? In this post, I look at the speeds on first and second serve and use a mixture model to identify the different power styles that are used by today&amp;rsquo;s top male players.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is the Approach Game Making a Comeback?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2020/10/02/approach-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2020/10/02/approach-trends/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve been tuning into the 2020 French Open and found yourself saying, &amp;lsquo;man, seems like guys are going to the net a lot&amp;rsquo;, you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be wrong. So far, the approach rate at RG this year is an average of 19 per 100 points compared to 17 per 100 points in 2019 and 15 per 100 points in 2017 and 2018. It may seem small, but an upward shift of this size requires multiple players to be going to the net at an above average rate. So who might be driving this shift? And is the shift more than a one-off?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serve Chronicles</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2020/08/10/serve-chronicles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2020/08/10/serve-chronicles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For any tennis player, the &lt;em&gt;serve&lt;/em&gt; is a delicate balance between power and control. How well do the best players in the world manage this balance? Guest blogger, &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ptea_test?s=20&#34;&gt;Peter Tea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;, uses decades of match data to examine trends in the serve leaders and losers among top-ranked ATP and WTA players.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Two First Serves are Better Than One - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2020/06/27/when-two-first-serves-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2020/06/27/when-two-first-serves-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Guest blogger, &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ptea_test?s=20&#34;&gt;Peter Tea&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;, returns for another chapter of the conundrum that is Alexander Zverev&amp;rsquo;s serve. In this second part of the &lt;em&gt;When Two First Serves are Better Than One&lt;/em&gt; series, Tea investigates the trends behind Zverev&amp;rsquo;s serve and attempts to identify the specific factors that have made him a surprising candidate for a two-first-serve strategy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Game the UTS Cards</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2020/06/21/uts-cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2020/06/21/uts-cards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Ultimate Tennis Showdown (UTS) is a new tennis league created by Patrick Mouratoglou that is aiming to attract younger fans to tennis. When the league debuted this month, it was clear that it was taking a lot of inspiration from e-sports, introducing more gaming features like UTS cards. These cards give players the chance to change the value of some points, adding extra chances for strategic advantage. So far, the players haven&amp;rsquo;t always seemed to know how to use the cards to their best advantage. In this post, I show how to estimate the expected value of each UTS card and rank them from most to least valuable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Two First Serves are Better Than One - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2020/06/17/when-two-first-serves-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2020/06/17/when-two-first-serves-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The contrast between the first and second serves can sometimes give the impression that pros have incredibly fine control of the risk of their serve, tuning the risk like the dial of a thermostat. But even for great players, risk control isn&amp;rsquo;t always easy. Sometimes the control of the second serve can get so out of whack that they are better off sticking with their first serve. This post, by guest blogger &lt;b&gt;Peter Tea&lt;/b&gt;, a masters student in statistics at Simon Fraser University, delves into when and for whom the two-first-serve strategy is a good option in tennis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charting the Longest Slam Matches of All Time</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2020/05/24/longest-all-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2020/05/24/longest-all-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The suspension of the tennis season has given tennis fans time for a number of side projects. In this post, I share the story of my side endeavour to make a central database of the results of all Grand Slams singles matches ever played. Thanks to Wikipedia and weeks of data wrangling, I can now share the first analysis on this blog that includes the entire history at the Majors: an analysis of the longest matches of all time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some of the Most Surprising Runs in Recent Grand Slam History</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2020/04/18/slam-surprise-runs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2020/04/18/slam-surprise-runs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With so much time these days to walk down tennis memory lane, I thought it would be fun to rank the wildest runs at the Grand Slams. In this post, I show how we can use the total gain in player ratings over an event to identify surprising individual results at the majors from the 1990s to the present.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What the World Wars Might Tell Us About Returning to Top Slam Form After a Long Hiatus From Play</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2020/03/28/war-hiatus-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2020/03/28/war-hiatus-impact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is no time in tennis history that compares to what tennis (or the world, for that matter) is going through right now. The World Wars were the only other time where multiple Majors were suspended for an extended period of time. In this post we look at the slam winners in the 10 years before and after World War I and II and consider what history might tell us about the difficulty of coming back from the public health war against COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Do I Watch Now (Part 2)?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2020/03/27/wta-best-matches/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2020/03/27/wta-best-matches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I described one strategy for using round, game margin, and total games to automatically rank interesting matches. After using this approach to rank the Top 30 men&amp;rsquo;s matches, in this post I do the same for the women for all Grand Slam matches from 1997 to the present.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Do I Watch Now?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2020/03/26/atp-best-matches/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2020/03/26/atp-best-matches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the tours and most nations now on lockdown, many of us are feeling bereft of matches to watch. If you have been looking for great classic matches to watch and wondered where to start, I&amp;rsquo;ve got you covered! Using an &amp;lsquo;interest&amp;rsquo; score that attempts to combine match length, competitiveness and quality, I&amp;rsquo;ve ranked the 30 most interesting men&amp;rsquo;s matches from 1990 to the present.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Top ATP Players Non-IID?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2020/03/20/non-iid-top50/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2020/03/20/non-iid-top50/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With sport at a standstill, there is ample time for sports nerds to get really wonky. In this post, I look at a question that should go to the heart of any tennis analyst: are players non-iid? I look at how we can measure non-iid effects, why we should care, and who has been the most non-iid among the Top 50 ATP players.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winners and Losers of a Rankings Hiatus</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2020/03/13/rankings-winners-losers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2020/03/13/rankings-winners-losers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The announcement of a 6-week suspension of the ATP Tour was just the latest in a series of disruptions of the tennis calendar owing to the COVID-19 pandemic. With no official decisions on whether players will retain their current ranking, I consider what the possible impact would be if the tours were to decide to carry current rankings forward for a prolonged period.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>March Methods Madness at the 2020 MIT Sloan Sports Analytics Conference</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2020/03/07/sloan-research-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2020/03/07/sloan-research-papers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since introducing the Research Paper Competition in 2010, the MIT Sloan Sports Analytics Conference has become one of the biggest stages for statistical research in sport. In this post, I review the methods used by the finalists and reflect on what this could suggest about current trends in statistical analysis in the sports industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build of Top 100 ATP Players 2000 vs 2020</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2020/02/29/atp-height-weight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2020/02/29/atp-height-weight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a recent article on Liverpool&amp;rsquo;s dominance of the English Premier League, John Burn-Murdoch created a visualization of the height and weight of EPL, NBA and NFL players. This got me interested in how current ATP players compare to the build of those other professional athletes and whether the build of top players has changed since the beginning of this century.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which Set Scores Are Most Likely for all Combinations of Servers?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2020/02/21/probable-set-scores/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2020/02/21/probable-set-scores/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In her debut match after nearly 8 years out of professional play, Kim Clijsters impressed many by taking Garbine Muguruza to a second set tiebreak. Neither player was winning more than 60% of points on serve, which made me wonder how likely a tiebreak was in this case. In this post, I use a simple Monte Carlo model to examine the most likely set scores for a variety of server matchups.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does greater competition load going into the second week of a Grand Slam hurt a player&#39;s win chances?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2020/02/15/competition-load/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2020/02/15/competition-load/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By the time of the Australian Open quarterfinals, Dominic Thiem had already played 10 hours and 23 minutes putting him in the top 20% of match time played to get to the quarters among men competing in Grand Slams in the past decade. And he only got further in the tail of total competition load as the event progressed. In this post, I look at whether the intensity of Thiem&amp;rsquo;s journey likely made his prospects for the title even more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is an Early Walkover an Advantage in a Slam?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2020/01/24/slam-walkover-advantage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2020/01/24/slam-walkover-advantage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a walkover from Kohlschreiber in the R64, Stefanos Tsitsipas advanced to the third round with one fewer match played this week than any of his competitors. As Tsitsipas takes the court today for a spot in the 4th round, we look at whether skipping a round of play could have an impact on his result at the first slam of the season.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Men&#39;s Title Chances for the 2020 Australian Open</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2020/01/17/mens-ao-title/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2020/01/17/mens-ao-title/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The draw for the 2020 Australian Open is out! What are the chances among the Big 3 for the first Grand Slam of the year? And is anyone else a strong prospect this year?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women&#39;s Title Chances for the 2020 Australian Open</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2020/01/17/womens-ao-title/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2020/01/17/womens-ao-title/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ash Barty will carry the expectations of a nation when the Australian Open gets underway in a few days. But the odds suggest the 2020 AO could be 5 times a charm in Major finals for Serena Williams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Were the Top Pressure Performers at the 2019 Grand Slams?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/11/15/pressure-win-stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/11/15/pressure-win-stats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I looked the the players who faced the most pressure at the Grand Slams in 2019. In this post, I ask the next obvious question. Who performed the best under high pressure?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Felt the Pressure the Most at the 2019 Grand Slams?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/11/08/pressure-stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/11/08/pressure-stats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the Grand Slam calendar for 2019 now at a close, which players faced the greatest challenges at the majors? And which achieved the most under extreme pressure?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are the First Years of the &#39;Next4&#39; Anything Like the Big4?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/10/24/next4-big4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/10/24/next4-big4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are likely to look back at the end of the 2019 season as the start of a generational breakthrough in men&amp;rsquo;s tennis. With four of the most impressive 23-and-unders on tour—Daniil Medvedev, Stefanos Tsitsipas, Alexander Zverev, and Matteo Berrettini—reaching the semifinals and taking out 2 of the Big 4 on their way there, it is feeling like we are on the brink of a &amp;lsquo;Big 4&amp;rsquo; takeover by the &amp;lsquo;Next 4&amp;rsquo;. What can the early career trajectories of the Big 4 tell us about which if any of these young stars might follow their footsteps?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Short Explainer on Getting to a Laver Cup Decider</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/09/24/laver-cup-decider/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/09/24/laver-cup-decider/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the third instalment of the Laver Cup, Team World came the closest it has ever come to defeating the juggernaut that Team Europe continues to be. With a Day 2 score of 5-7, World, in taking the first two matches, made the contest as close as it could have been. There was some confusion about that fact by the TV commentators who seemed to think that it was still possible for the teams to get to a 13th match. Here I explain why that wasn&amp;rsquo;t the case and what would have had to happen to reach a decider.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Medvedev and Berrettini Dealt with Pressure at the US Open</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/09/13/us-open-pressure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/09/13/us-open-pressure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The performances of Daniil Medvedev and Matteo Berrettini at the 2019 US Open showed that the future of men&amp;rsquo;s tennis is bright. In this post, I look at the point-by-point pressure each of these young stars had to confront and analyze how well they responded to it in each round of their US Open journey.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ages at the US Open are Getting Bimodal, Again</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/09/06/us-open-ages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/09/06/us-open-ages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With 22 year-old Belinda Bencic, 19 year-old Bianca Andreescu, and twenty-three year-olds Daniil Medvedev and Matteo Berrettini into the US Open semifinals; are we seeing the first wave of a new generation of dominant players at Majors?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Which Blockbuster Matches Might Be Ahead At The US Open?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/08/30/us-open-blockbusters/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/08/30/us-open-blockbusters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The round of 32 is set for the US Open. Out of all the matches that could still happen, which will be the ones not to miss?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Has the Momentum Going into the US Open?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/08/23/us-open-momentum/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/08/23/us-open-momentum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the last Grand Slam of the calendar approaching, it is the perfect time to review the relative strengths of the field and who has done the most to increase their hardcourt edge in the past year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Possible Effects of Abolishing First Service or Advantage Points</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/08/16/abolishing-first-serve/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/08/16/abolishing-first-serve/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The format changes at Majors are the most prominent of a number of rule changes that are being considered to reduce the length of tennis matches in order to make the tennis &amp;lsquo;product&amp;rsquo; more attractive. In this guest post, Francesco Lisi and Matteo Grigoletto of the Department of Statistical
Sciences at the University of Padua investigate how removing the first serve or advantage points could impact match lengths.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Stat for Must-See Matches</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/08/09/must-see-matches/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/08/09/must-see-matches/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A constant conundrum for tennis fans is deciding which match to watch at any particular time. In this post, I look at how we can quanitfy the &amp;lsquo;must-seeness&amp;rsquo; of a match based on it&amp;rsquo;s overall quality and competitiveness using player ratings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Player Ratings Tables Go Live!</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/07/19/updating-player-ratings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/07/19/updating-player-ratings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new section of the website is debuted: &amp;lsquo;Ratings&amp;rsquo;. Here (the hope) is to provide the top 100 singles and doubles men and women on tour each week using MOV Elo ratings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unicorns of the WTA</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/07/12/wta-unicorns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/07/12/wta-unicorns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the US Open hard court swing just around the corner, Ash Barty heads into the last leg of the season with the highest rating in women&amp;rsquo;s singles and doubles. Such simultaneous dominance in singles and doubles has, in the past decade, only been matched by Serena Williams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early Ups and Downs on Clay</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/04/26/ups-downs-clay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/04/26/ups-downs-clay/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After the first weeks of the clay season, who is making fwaves and who has had a wipe out? Here are men&amp;rsquo;s and women&amp;rsquo;s twenty biggest movers so far on clay.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Putting a Basic Playing Style Classifier to the Test</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/04/19/testing-match-stats-and-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/04/19/testing-match-stats-and-style/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Any measure of playing style is only as good as what it can explain beyond player overall ability. If we apply this standard to playing style categories derived from basic match stats, how do they hold up?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Exploration on Using Match Stats to Classify Playing Styles</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/04/12/match-stats-and-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/04/12/match-stats-and-style/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, I looked at whether basic match stats, like aces and minutes played per point, could help describe a player&amp;rsquo;s playing style. In this post, I expand on the set of style features and delve into the clusters of playing styles they reveal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Can Match Stats Tell Us About Playing Styles?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/04/05/match-stats-and-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/04/05/match-stats-and-style/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve had a few posts on head-to-head effects. The biggest takeaway was one we probably all knew going in: Head-to-head effects may exist, but good luck finding them. With so many small sample sizes for most head-to-heads, we need a way to group &amp;lsquo;similar&amp;rsquo; players. In this post, I look at whether categorizing players by playing style might be possible using basic match stats.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top Pressure Performances in March</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/03/29/top-pressure-performances/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/03/29/top-pressure-performances/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ahead of the final matches in Miami this weekend, we look back on the players who triumphed in the face of the most pressure-filled matches so far this month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WTA Head-to-Head Effects</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/03/22/head-to-head-effects-wta/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/03/22/head-to-head-effects-wta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you thought Serena vs Maria was a lopsided head-to-head, you are right. But it isn&amp;rsquo;t the biggest head-to-head effect in recent WTA history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Head-to-Head Effects</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/03/15/head-to-head-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/03/15/head-to-head-effects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Matchup effects are a common idea in tennis commentary. It is the thing at the heart of comments like &amp;lsquo;her game matches up well&amp;rsquo; against her opponent. One way to think of a matchup effect is as a surprising head-to-head, when results go against what the overall ability of both players would have us expect. Do such effects exist? And are they substantial enough that they matter when it comes to making better predictions about tennis results?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Men&#39;s Title Predictions for Indian Wells</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/03/07/indian-wells-atp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/03/07/indian-wells-atp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Novak Djokovic looked unstoppable at the Australian Open and he heads into Indian Wells as the hands down favourite for the title. With GIG predictions giving him a 1 and 2 chance to win the whole thing, the question of the event will be whether anyone can stop Djokovic?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women&#39;s Title Predictions for Indian Wells</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/03/06/indian-wells-wta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/03/06/indian-wells-wta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The women&amp;rsquo;s draw for the first of the Sunshine Double is out. In this post, I break down the prospects for the 10 women most likely to impress at Indian Wells this year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Men&#39;s Top Pressure Performances in February</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/03/01/atp-bpe-feb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/03/01/atp-bpe-feb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the close of the second month of the 2019 season, we look back at the biggest pressure performances of the men&amp;rsquo;s tour. Reilley Opelka takes top honours for having faced the most service pressure in a match in February, racking up 15.5 break point equivalents (BPEs) against John Isner in New York. Opelka also saved the most of the BPEs faces winning a whopping 92% of high-pressure service points.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the Fit of a Serve Prediction Model</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/02/22/serve-model-check/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/02/22/serve-model-check/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A model that could predict a player&amp;rsquo;s performance on serve would have a number of interesting uses like forecasting the outcome of matches or identifying surprising performances. But for any of these uses the model would need to be accurate and reliable. How should we evaluate a model&amp;rsquo;s performance? And how do we know when a model is good enough?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identifying Surprising Performances with Prediction Intervals</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/02/15/serve-prediction-interval/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/02/15/serve-prediction-interval/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every player has days when everything seems to work and other days when nothing seems to go right. Saying when a player has truly over (or under) performed is tricky in tennis because there is always an opponent on the other side of the net that is also influencing the outcome of points. In this post, I look at a basic strategy to try to isolate the ability of the server and receiver, and discuss how this might be used to identify surprising performances on serve.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Best Quantify Service Pressure</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/01/29/break-point-units/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/01/29/break-point-units/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pressure is one of those concepts in tennis that we all know exists but we struggle to calculate. I&amp;rsquo;ve made multiple attempts at quantifying scoreboard pressure and have yet to come around to one that is both statistically useful and easy to interpret. But some recent experimenting has uncovered what I think could be as close to a &amp;lsquo;best&amp;rsquo; statistic for pressure as I am likely to find.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do Numbers Back Up A Changing of the Guard at the 2019 Australian Open?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/01/21/ao-changing-guard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/01/21/ao-changing-guard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In his win over Roger Federer, 20 year-old Stefanos Tsitsipas not only earned the biggest upset of the 2019 Australian Open so far, he caused many to wonder whether tennis was seeing the start of a new era. Tsitsipas&amp;rsquo;s journey at the 2019 AO is the biggest of multiple success stories for a young crop of talents on the men&amp;rsquo;s tour, stories that have already made this year one of the most unique in AO history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of the New Super Tiebreak at the Australian Open</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/01/18/ao-tiebreak10-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/01/18/ao-tiebreak10-impact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The introduction of a super tiebreak in the deciding set of singles matches was one of a number of changes at the 2019 Australian Open. After two rounds, 3 men&amp;rsquo;s and 2 women&amp;rsquo;s matches have already put that rule to the test. What do the outcomes of those matches tell us about the possible impact of the new format?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictions for the 2018 Australian Open Men&#39;s Draw</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/01/13/ao-mens-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/01/13/ao-mens-preview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ahead of the first round of the Australian Open, I take a look at some of the likely winners on the men&amp;rsquo;s side. The forecast bodes well for the Big 3, with Novak Djokovic leading the race toward the first slam title of the 2019 season.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictions for the 2018 Australian Open Women&#39;s Draw</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/01/13/ao-womens-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/01/13/ao-womens-preview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ahead of the first round of the Australian Open, I take a look at the top prospects for the women&amp;rsquo;s title at the Australian Open. Could it be Karolina Pliskova&amp;rsquo;s year?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Has Experienced the Most and Least Set Pressure this Season?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/11/17/experienced-pressure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/11/17/experienced-pressure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After introducing &lt;em&gt;Pressure Ratings&lt;/em&gt; for matches, this post looks at how a similar approach can be used to develop a &lt;em&gt;Set Competitiveness&lt;/em&gt; rating for players. The &lt;em&gt;Set Competitiveness&lt;/em&gt; measures the pressure of a player&amp;rsquo;s sets in a way that allows direct ranking against the pressure typically faced by other players.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Pressure Ratings to Rank Most Competitive Matches in 2018</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/11/09/match-pressure-ratings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/11/09/match-pressure-ratings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week&amp;rsquo;s 252-point Paris Masters semifinal between Novak Djokovic and Roger Federer got many wondering whether it was the best match in their 47 match long rivalry. In this post, I introduce a pressure rating for sets and matches that can help to tell us to rate their relative competitiveness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Djokovic Regains No. 1 But His Climb in the Ratings Isn&#39;t Over</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/11/02/djokovic-improving-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/11/02/djokovic-improving-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Monday, Novak Djokovic will regain the World No. 1 ranking, climbing from outside the top 20 at the start of the year. Djokovic&amp;rsquo;s comeback has been the major story this week. In this post, I look at his rise in terms of his match-by-match Elo rating and put it in context of his best season performances in 2011 and 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting to the 2018 WTA Finals--An Elo Story</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/10/20/wta-finals-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/10/20/wta-finals-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2018 WTA Finals is upon us. With Simona Halep bowing out of the event, Caroline Wozniacki enters with the highest GIG Elo Rating. But what do the ratings trajectories of the 8 competitors reveal about who could have the most momentum and confidence heading into Singapore?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Djokovic and Bertens, Two of the Most Improved Players in 2018</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/10/14/elo-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/10/14/elo-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Novak Djokovic could continue a masterful run toward the end of the season when he goes for his second 2018 Masters 1000 title against Borna Coric in Shanghai. Even before the final, Djokovic sits at the top of men&amp;rsquo;s current all-surface Elo ratings. In this post we look at the how the current top 8 on the men&amp;rsquo;s and women&amp;rsquo;s tours have won there place among the ratings leaders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Weekly Earnings Opportunity to Measure the Prize Money Gender Gap</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/10/04/prize-money-opportunities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/10/04/prize-money-opportunities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Prize money has been the primary yardstick for measuring gender inequality in professional tennis. Most in-depth studies of prize money differences have focused on earnings of top players or prize money commitments by tournament. In this post, I take a different view on prize money differences by focusing on earning opportunities in each week of the the tour calendar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Europe Readies to Defend Laver Cup Title</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/09/19/laver-cup-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/09/19/laver-cup-preview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following it&amp;rsquo;s successful debut in 2017, the Laver Cup will makes its second edition this week. Defending champions Team Europe will meet Team World in Chicago, with new teammates joining each side. In this post, I look at how competitive the 2018 instalment of Laver Cup is shaping up to be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zverev&#39;s US Open Loss Puts Him Among Top 20 Most Disappointing Major Performances So Far</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/09/04/slam-disappointment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/09/04/slam-disappointment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are into the quarterfinals at the 2018 US Open. No matter what happens in the final days of the event, we already know that one of the major storylines of this year will be Alexander Zverev&amp;rsquo;s failure to get to the second week. Zverev&amp;rsquo;s third round loss to Philipp Kohlschreiber makes the 14th loss at a slam, 13 of which have been before the quarterfinals. With this slam record, what hopes does the twenty-one year-old have for getting that elusive first Major?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 US Open Still The Most Brutal in Tennis History</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/08/31/us-open-retirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/08/31/us-open-retirements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After two rounds in extreme heat conditions, the 2018 US Open has seen 12 men&amp;rsquo;s singles matches end in retirement. Is this a historic high for the number of early retirements at a slam? And how do high retirement counts impact the progress of the draw?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plus-Minus Statistics for Tennis</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/08/26/plus-minus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/08/26/plus-minus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Plus-Minus doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be a stat for team sports only. This post introduces Plus-Minus for tennis and uses it to rank the leaders on serve and return heading into the US Open.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Is the Teen GOAT of Men&#39;s Tennis?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/08/18/teen-goat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/08/18/teen-goat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Stefanos Tsitsipas became the youngest player to beat four top 10 players in a single event at the Rogers Cup, many were wondering about the greatest teen performances in tennis history. This post looks at top contenders for &amp;lsquo;Teenage GOAT&amp;rsquo; status in the men&amp;rsquo;s game and how they compare to recent impressive teens.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Carpet to Blame for an Unpredictable Grass Court Season?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/07/28/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/07/28/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many are still trying to get their heads around the poor showing of top players at the 2018 Wimbledon. In this post we look at what role the number of opportunities to play on grass might have had.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does WTA Depth Explain How Wild 2018 Wimbledon Was?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/07/20/wimbledon-wta-depth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/07/20/wimbledon-wta-depth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the 2018 Wimbledon, the women&amp;rsquo;s seeds struggled to an unprecedented degree. Was this bad luck? Or a sign of the competitiveness of the women&amp;rsquo;s tour?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wimbledon Seeds - Just How Unprecedented Are All These Early Exits?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/07/06/wimbledon-seeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/07/06/wimbledon-seeds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Record numbers of seeds are falling in the early rounds at Wimbledon.
We look at exactly how unprecedented these results are, whether this is part of a larger trend, and which first-round shock was the most unexpected.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Federer has outperformed everyone on grass - including himself</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/06/29/federer-wimbledon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/06/29/federer-wimbledon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With his haul of 8 titles, Roger Federer has triumphed at Wimbledon more than anyone else. But how does 8 titles compare with how many we could have expected him to win given his level—and his competition—over the years? And which title was his most impressive? [Authored by Graeme Spence]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top WTA Prospects for a First Slam at Wimbledon</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/06/22/wta-first-slam/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/06/22/wta-first-slam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With Wimbledon a little more than a week away, we look at the trends in first slams for the WTA and the top prospects for the next first-slam winner at SW19.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Interrupting a Match Impact the Outcome?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/06/08/suspended-impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/06/08/suspended-impact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The intermittent rain and late nights at the 2018 French Open have resulted in multiple interrupted matches, including the bottom half of the men&amp;rsquo;s quarterfinals. We often have the impression that reversals and big swings are more likely with an interrupted match. Does the data back up this impression of the impact of suspended play?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Will Freshness be a Factor at the French Open?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/06/05/freshness-factor/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/06/05/freshness-factor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In reaching the quarterfinal at the 2018 French Open, Alexander Zverev not only has earned the best Grand Slam result of his career, he also joins a short list of 4 men in the Open Era who have played 3 or more five-set matches on their way to the Roland Garros quarterfinals. Is Zverev&amp;rsquo;s gruelling journey to the second week most likely to hurt or help his chances for the title?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Previewing the 22nd Match of Maria and Serena - Will History Repeat Itself?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/06/04/maria-serena/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/06/04/maria-serena/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, as part of the final R16 lineup at the French Open, Serena Williams will have the opportunity to bring her near-perfect record over Maria Sharapova to a staggering 20 to 2. Many have wondered how much Williams&#39; dominance over the &amp;lsquo;Unstoppable&amp;rsquo; author is fuelled by more than pure ability. In this post, we attempt to understand the &lt;i&gt;inexplicable&lt;/i&gt; part of their head-to-head.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Surface Specialists a Dying Breed?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/06/01/surface-specialisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/06/01/surface-specialisation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The red dirt of Roland Garros, which has held the attention of the tennis world this week, is the most defining feature of the only clay-court Grand Slam. But, when it comes to performance, is clay losing its distinctiveness? In this guest post, Graeme Spence, delves into the closing gap in surface specialisation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Patterns Can We Expect From Nadal at the French?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/05/27/nadal-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/05/27/nadal-patterns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The main draw of the 2018 French Open is just hours away and Rafael Nadal is the frontrunner by far for the title. What patterns of play have contributed to the 10-time champion&amp;rsquo;s clay dominance in 2018?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>French Open Predictions</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/05/26/french-open-predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/05/26/french-open-predictions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are a day away from the first round of the 2018 French Open. Who are tennis fans most likely to see in the final stages of the event? And who among the top contenders were favoured by this year&amp;rsquo;s draw?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most Improved Among French Open Seeds</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/05/26/french-open-confidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/05/26/french-open-confidence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As tennis prepares for the second slam of the season, we look at the players who have raised their game the most in the past year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alexander Zverev&#39;s Evolution on Clay</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/05/18/zverev-evolution-clay/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/05/18/zverev-evolution-clay/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alexander Zverev has a chance to bag a second clay-court Masters title for the year having already reached the quarterfinals in Rome. Whether he defends his Rome title or not, 2018 is shaping up to be Zverev&amp;rsquo;s best career performance on clay so far. How has he managed to raise his game on the red dirt?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzling Head-to-Heads in Women&#39;s Tennis History</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/05/10/surprising-head-to-head-wta/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/05/10/surprising-head-to-head-wta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week we looked at some of the biggest mismatches in the men&amp;rsquo;s game. What does the same analysis tell us about the most baffling women&amp;rsquo;s head-to-heads?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sizing Up Surprising Head-to-Heads</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/05/06/surprising-head-to-head/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/05/06/surprising-head-to-head/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why is it that some players seem to consistently underperform against certain opponents? And how could we measure the all-time most surprising head-to-heads in the game?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Novak Just Need More Match Play?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/04/27/novak-match-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/04/27/novak-match-play/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Novak Djokovic&amp;rsquo;s first round loss in Barcelona this week is making many wonder what, if anything, can get the Serbian back to his peak form.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In His Return, Nadal is Making Every Minute Count</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/04/25/nadal-clay-dominance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/04/25/nadal-clay-dominance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With his first major clay event in 2018, Nadal has set the stage for one of the most efficient clay seasons of his career.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nadal Set for a 2017 Clay Season Repeat</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/04/14/nadal-2017-repeat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/04/14/nadal-2017-repeat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the tour prepares for Monte Carlo, Rafael Nadal finds himself at the top of the clay-adjusted Elo ratings for the first time since 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clutch Stats from the Sunshine Masters</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/04/07/sunshine-masters-clutch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/04/07/sunshine-masters-clutch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the tours head into the clay court season, who should be buoyed the most by their mental toughness during Indian Wells and Miami?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of Del Potro&#39;s Backhand</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/04/01/delpotro-backhand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/04/01/delpotro-backhand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this guest blog, &lt;a href=&#34;@xenophar&#34;&gt;Martin Ingram&lt;/a&gt; analyses the dramatic trends in the backhand of La Torre de Tandil using Gaussian processes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the WTA Has Gotten More Competitive</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/04/01/wta-competitive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/04/01/wta-competitive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sloane Stephens had to get past 3 former No. 1s and 4 Grand Slam winners to take the Miami Open title this weekend. Is everyone&amp;rsquo;s path to a Premier final getting tougher?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is the Changing of the Guard Coming?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/03/31/changing-guard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/03/31/changing-guard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Next Gen have been center stage throughout the Sunshine Masters this year. How can we size up the success of the young guns? And what does their success mean for the rest of the 2018 season?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasts for the 2018 Miami Masters Title</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/03/21/miami-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/03/21/miami-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a near perfect first quarter of the season, Roger Federer enters the Miami Masters with a 50-50 chance of winning the title, thanks in part to the luck of the draw.  Who are the other biggest male and female contenders for the Key Biscayne title?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cape Town celebrates R and tennis data science at satRday</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/03/16/satrday-capetown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/03/16/satrday-capetown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While Roger Federer earned his 17th straight win of 2018, tennis data science was taking a center stage at Cape Town&amp;rsquo;s satRday conference.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Tiafoe&#39;s win in Delray Beach only the beginning?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/03/03/nextgen-winnners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/03/03/nextgen-winnners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the more interesting ATP results this February was 20-year-old Francis Tiafoe&amp;rsquo;s title win at Delray Beach. What should we expect from Tiafoe after his first tour-level trophy at such a young age?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Highlights from 2018 MIT Sloan Analytics Conference</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/02/23/ssac-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/02/23/ssac-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;style&gt;
.table-striped&gt;tbody&gt;tr:nth-child(odd)&gt;td, 
.table-striped&gt;tbody&gt;tr:nth-child(odd)&gt;th {
background-color: #cee454; // Choose your own color here
}
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week the MIT Sloan Analytics Conference will showcase some of the cutting-edge research happening in sports statistics. What do the themes from this year suggest about the state-of-the-art in quantitative work in sport?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AO to AI Hackathon Winners Announced</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/02/19/ao-hackathon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/02/19/ao-hackathon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As Roger Federer was crowned with his 20th Grand Slam title at the 2018 Australian Open, the winners of the first AO to AI Hackathon competition were being decided. In this post, I take a look at the winning models and discuss what they mean for the future of calling point outcomes in tennis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slam Seeding - Is 16 Better than 32?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/02/02/slam-seeding-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/02/02/slam-seeding-changes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting in 2019, Grand Slams will have just 16 seeds. Top players have expressed concerns that this change will make it harder for them to advance to the latter stages of Majors and make for less competitive matches as the events progress. Are they right?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Slam Momentum a Thing?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/01/25/slam-momentum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/01/25/slam-momentum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With two heavy outsiders into the men&amp;rsquo;s semifinals, does the outcome of the men&amp;rsquo;s draw become a foregone conclusion? Or should momentum raise our expectations for the underdogs?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Odds Are Against Quick Comebacks</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/01/22/quick-comebacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/01/22/quick-comebacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After 6 months out of action owing to an elbow injury, Novak Djokovic is one match away from a quarterfinal at the Australian Open. Djokovic is on track to make a strong return in Melbourne. But how unusual is a fast comeback after injury? What can most top players who have delayed their 2018 return expect about the difficulty of reaching their previous form?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting the Women&#39;s 2018 Australian Open</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/01/13/ao-womens-draw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/01/13/ao-womens-draw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A strong pre-AO run and a bit of luck put Elina Svitolina at the top of a tight race for the Australian Open women&amp;rsquo;s title. Who are the other women with the best chances for the first Major win of 2018?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting the Men&#39;s 2018 Australian Open</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/01/12/ao-mens-draw/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/01/12/ao-mens-draw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Roger Federer drew the toughest quarter of the 2018 Men&amp;rsquo;s Australian Open draw but is still the favourite to defend his title. Who else is a contender for the men&amp;rsquo;s title?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have Gruelling Schedules Caught Up With the Top of Men&#39;s Tennis?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/01/06/game-age/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/01/06/game-age/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Andy Murray&amp;rsquo;s withdrawal from the Australian Open topped the list of a series of unfortunate absences to start the men&amp;rsquo;s 2018 tennis season. Are the physical demands of the current game causing burn out at the top of the sport?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Men&#39;s Surface Performances in 2017</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/12/16/serve-return-surface-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/12/16/serve-return-surface-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Who dominated each surface in 2017? This post breaks down the best clay, hard, and grass performers on the men&amp;rsquo;s tour this year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best WTA Servers and Returners of 2017</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/12/09/serve-return-wta-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/12/09/serve-return-wta-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2017 has been a wide-open year for the WTA. What do Elo ratings tell us about the standout serve and return performances of the season?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best ATP Servers and Returners of 2017</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/12/02/serve-return-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/12/02/serve-return-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Who was the best server in 2017? Who was the best receiver? Which players were the most improved servers and receivers? This post reviews the standout performances of male players in 2017 using serve/return Elo ratings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sizing Up Federer&#39;s Seasons</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/11/23/federer-seasons/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/11/23/federer-seasons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;resurgence&amp;rdquo; of Roger Federer has been one of the biggest storylines of the 2017 season. After the end of Federer&amp;rsquo;s season at the ATP Tour Finals, how does it rank among his past seasons? and what is the best metric for judging season accomplishments?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serve and Return Elo Ratings</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/11/18/elo-serve-return/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/11/18/elo-serve-return/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Elo rating system is one of the most popular tools for rating player and team performance. In this post, I show how we can take the Elo system beyond match wins and use it to rate players on the two most fundamental skills in the sport: serving and returning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Many Sides of Excitement</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/11/10/excitement-indices/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/11/10/excitement-indices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having a metric for match excitement would be a useful tool for separating humdrum matches from thrillers. In this post, I have a look at two indices for measuring match excitement and discuss what&amp;rsquo;s to like and dislike about each.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Stat for Excitement and What It Reveals About the Best Men&#39;s Matches at the 2017 US Open</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/11/03/us-open-excitement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/11/03/us-open-excitement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2017 MLB World Series gave baseball fans a thrill-ride for the post-season. It also gives us an idea of how to size up the excitement of a sporting event. In this post, we look at an &amp;lsquo;excitement&amp;rsquo; statistic for tennis and use it to rank the excitement of men&amp;rsquo;s matches at the 2017 US Open.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shot Quality Maps</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/10/27/shot-quality-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/10/27/shot-quality-maps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine you could measure the quality of every shot during a tennis match. What would it reveal about a player&amp;rsquo;s performance and where on the court they perform best?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Fatigue Cumulative?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/10/20/cumulative-fatigue-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/10/20/cumulative-fatigue-effects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fighting off fatigue in any Grand Slam match is a challenge. Does this get even harder after multiple matches?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Match Fatigue</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/10/13/fatigue-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/10/13/fatigue-effects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A talk at the recent New England Symposium on Statistics in Sport (NESSIS) made me wonder whether we can observe player fatigue in tennis matches? and how?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing Scoreboard Effects</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/10/06/scoreboard-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/10/06/scoreboard-effects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do the numbers on the scoreboard affect how a player performs? In this post, we look at how to measure scoreboard effects and identify some top players who appear vulnerable and others who seem impervious to the scoreboard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women&#39;s Slam Strength Also Down in 2017</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/09/30/slam-strength-wta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/09/30/slam-strength-wta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2016, Angelique Kerber and Garbine Muguruza shocked tennis with Major wins. This year, Jelena Ostapenko and Sloane Stephens were the unexpected first-time slam title-holders. Who, if any of these winners, were helped by an easier Grand Slam field?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decline of Men&#39;s Slam Strength in 2017</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/09/16/slam-strength-decline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/09/16/slam-strength-decline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that the US Open—the last of the four Majors of the tennis calendar—has ended, it is more clear than ever that the 2017 season has been a strange one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Were the Odds of an All-American Women&#39;s SF at the US Open?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/09/08/all-american-sf-odds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/09/08/all-american-sf-odds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the first time in 36 years, the US Open women&amp;rsquo;s singles event will have an all-American semifinal. What were the odds of this historic outcome?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2016 US Open Men Would Smash 2017</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/09/02/weak-us-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/09/02/weak-us-open/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There has been a lot of talk about the lacklustre men&amp;rsquo;s field at this year&amp;rsquo;s US Open. What better way to put this idea to the test than to have the 2017 US Open men&amp;rsquo;s draw go head-to-head against the draw of 2016?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Has Too Much Play Finally Caught Up with Top Men?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/08/26/too-much-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/08/26/too-much-play/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2017 US Open draw is out. But much of the talk this year will be on the names not included in the draw.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most Surprising Runs in Men&#39;s Open Era</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/08/20/most-surprising-runs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/08/20/most-surprising-runs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this guest post, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Xenophar&#34;&gt;Martin Ingram&lt;/a&gt; explores the stats behind surprising runs in tennis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Match Dominance Among Next Gen</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/08/19/next-gen-bp-plus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/08/19/next-gen-bp-plus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The US hard court season has been a breakout period for the ATP tour&amp;rsquo;s Next Gen players. In this post we look at which Next Gen players have been the most dominant this season.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sizing Up Tournament Strength and Depth</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/08/11/tournament-strength/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/08/11/tournament-strength/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tournament &lt;em&gt;strength&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;depth&lt;/em&gt; are terms we commonly hear used in tennis. Yet the sport doesn&amp;rsquo;t have good stats for either of these properties of events.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is 2017 Federer that Different than 2015 Federer?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/07/28/federer-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/07/28/federer-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With just one Grand Slam remaining in the 2017 season, it is already clear that one of the biggest stories of the year will be the renaissance of Roger Federer and Rafael Nadal&amp;rsquo;s dominance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most Surprising at Wimbledon 2017</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/07/22/wimbledon-surprise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/07/22/wimbledon-surprise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Which players exceeded expectations the most at the 2017 Wimbledon Championships? Which, on the other hand, had the most shocking exits?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring Match Dominance</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/07/16/match-dominance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/07/16/match-dominance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a few hours, Roger Federer will face Marin Cilic on Wimbledon&amp;rsquo;s Centre Court where he will play for his 19th Grand Slam and 8th Wimbledon title.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wimbledon R16 Leaders</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/07/09/wimbledon-r16-leaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/07/09/wimbledon-r16-leaders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After 6 hot days of competition, a spate of retirements, and some battling with flying ants, the line-up for the round of 16 at the 2017 Wimbledon Championships is set.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Men&#39;s Serve and Return Grass Leaders</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/07/03/grass-leaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/07/03/grass-leaders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The most storied of tennis championships gets underway this week in the serene English borough at SW19.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women&#39;s Serve and Return Grass Leaders</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/07/03/womens-grass-leaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/07/03/womens-grass-leaders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Johanna Konta tops the serve and return grass leaderboards going into the women&amp;rsquo;s draw at the 2017 Wimbledon Championships.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Serena Williams Isn&#39;t the 700th Player By Any Measure</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/06/27/serena-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/06/27/serena-defense/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While tennis&#39; top players have been spending this week making their final preparations for the upcoming 2017 Wimbledon Championships, one tennis commentator has been stirring up controversy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2017 WTA Season Looking A Lot Like Early 2003</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/06/18/wta-elo-epochs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/06/18/wta-elo-epochs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the major tennis storylines of 2017 has been the opening up of the field on the WTA tour.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a number of former dominant players, like Serena Williams and Victoria Azarenka, out of the game and others, like Maria Sharapova and Petra Kvitova, still early in their return, 2017 has presented a massive opportunity to the tour&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;rising stars. Out of 13 Premier and Grand Slam events completed this season, 10 different women have taken the title win. This has given tennis fans many possible picks for who will emerge as the next major threat on the WTA tour.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>French Open ATP Leaders</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/06/11/french-open-atp-leaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/06/11/french-open-atp-leaders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After one shocking title winner took the ladies&#39; crown on Saturday at the French Open, the tennis world is abuzz with speculation about whether Stan Wawrinka will be able to deny Rafael Nadal a tenth title when they meet in the men&amp;rsquo;s final this afternoon?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>French Open WTA Leaders</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/06/10/french-open-wta-leaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/06/10/french-open-wta-leaders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are just hours away from the women&amp;rsquo;s final at the 2017 French Open. After 126 matches, 25 year-old Simona Halep and 20 year-old Jelena Ostapenko are the last women&amp;rsquo;s players remaining. And, whatever the outcome on Saturday in Paris, the women&amp;rsquo;s tour will see a new French Open champion and new Grand Slam title-holder crowned.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Women&#39;s French Open Seedings</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/06/03/womens-seeds-french-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/06/03/womens-seeds-french-open/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It only took a few days of main draw play for the 2017 French Open to give fodder to debates on the unpredictability of this year&amp;rsquo;s women&amp;rsquo;s tour. After two rounds, just 9 of the 32 seeds survived to the round of 32, 23 fewer than expected. Those numbers caused &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tennis.com/pro-game/2017/06/tennis-channel-roland-garros-2017-wta-player-draft-update-french-open/66477/&#34;&gt;tennis.com&lt;/a&gt; to conclude that the women&amp;rsquo;s draw was &amp;ldquo;decimated&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clay Court Performance Trends of French Open Title Men&#39;s Top 4</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/05/27/mens-clay-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/05/27/mens-clay-trends/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The French Open draw is out and Round 1 is only hours away. Four of the names that will be watched closely on the men&amp;rsquo;s side are 9-time champion Rafael Nadal, defending champion Novak Djokovic, defending finalist Andy Murray, and aspiring title-contender Dominic Thiem.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Return Leaders Among ATP&#39;s Top Contenders for French Open Title</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/05/22/top-contenders-french-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/05/22/top-contenders-french-open/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I took a look at the clay-court serve performance of four of the ATP players most in contention for the 2017 Roland Garros title— Rafael Nadal, Dominic Thiem, Novak Djokovic and Andy Murray. &lt;a href=&#34;http://on-the-t.com/2017/05/21/Top-Contenders-French-Open/&#34;&gt;That analysis&lt;/a&gt; showed that Rafael Nadal has so far separated himself on serve by 5 to 15 percentage points on average. An impressive stat next to anyone but especially when compared to the players who are some of his toughest rivals for another Major win.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serve Leaders Among ATP&#39;s Top Contenders for French Open Title</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/05/21/top-contenders-french-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/05/21/top-contenders-french-open/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that the dust has settled at the Rome Masters, the tennis world is turning its focus to the French Open, where main draw play is nearly upon us. With Roger Federer skipping Roland Garros when not injured for the first time since he first played the event in 1999, the four names that will be most in the discussion for the win are Rafael Nadal, Dominic Thiem, Novak Djokovic and Andy Murray. In this post, we look at the clay court season so far and what it tells us about the form for each of these top contenders going into the second Major of the year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WTA Tennis Rankings Aren&#39;t Working</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/05/20/new-ranking-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/05/20/new-ranking-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In her first match at the Rome Masters, World No. 1 Kerber was ousted by 
the 68th ranked player on tour, Anett Kontaveit, in straight sets. Despite holding the best rank on tour, Kerber has seemed in a slump for most of the season with early round loses becoming a norm.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should We Be Surprised by Murray&#39;s 2017 Clay Performance So Far?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/05/15/clayray-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/05/15/clayray-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At this point in the clay season, many of us were expecting Andy Murray to have appeared in at least one or more finals and maybe even snagged a title. But with a Round of 16 loss this week to Borna Coric at the Mutua Madrid Open, Murray has crashed out earlier than expected for his third clay court event of the season.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Officials Are Human Too</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/05/07/official-bias/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/05/07/official-bias/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every match win involves some luck. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s the coin toss or the bounce off a clipped net, some events in a tennis match are outside of a player&amp;rsquo;s control. And the sport accepts that. But we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t accept it when it comes to line calls, especially when there is technology that can prevent line call errors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Net Points Murray&#39;s Kryptonite?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/04/29/murray-serve-volley/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/04/29/murray-serve-volley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite starting the 2017 season as World No. 1 for the first time in his career, Andy Murray has had a lackluster go of it so far. After Murray&amp;rsquo;s Round of 16 loss at the Monte Carlo Masters last week, his match record was 13 and 4. Now, in terms of wins and losses alone, that puts him on par with his performances thru the end of April in 2016 and 2014, but far behind his record in 2015 when he had bagged 23 wins and just 5 losses by this point in the calendar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can Serena Williams be a Champion and Mom?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/04/21/serena-return/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/04/21/serena-return/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The tennis world is abuzz with speculation over the future of Serena Williams. In an already extraordinary week in which the 23 Grand Slam title-owning champion was projected to reclaim the World No. 1 without having played an event since this year&amp;rsquo;s Australian Open, Williams, in a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.telegraph.co.uk/tennis/2017/04/19/serena-williams-reveals-20-weeks-pregnant/&#34;&gt;cheeky snapchat post&lt;/a&gt;, announced that she was expecting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Easily Can Sharapova Return to the Top of the Game?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/04/14/sharapova-return/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/04/14/sharapova-return/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With less than 2 weeks until Maria Sharapova makes her return, there is a growing stir of speculation over her comeback. Having already been granted controversial wild cards and 3 Premier events, including the upcoming &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tennis.com/pro-game/2017/03/caroline-wozniacki-venus-williams-maria-sharapova-wildcard-stuttgart/64746/&#34;&gt;Stuttgart Grand Prix&lt;/a&gt;, Sharapova—after 15 months out of the game—will return to tennis with a unique opportunity to avoid the usual entry prohibitions of unranked players. Her first match will be in the middle of the first round of Stuttgart on April 26th where she will have a chance to take 470 ranking points.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Federer&#39;s 2017 Season His Best Start Ever?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/04/06/best-starts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/04/06/best-starts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After the first quarter of the 2017 season, Roger Federer has his 18th Grand Slam title and a 19-1 win record overall. Such an impressive start naturally leads us to ask: Where should we rank Federer&amp;rsquo;s 2017 start against the other seasons of his career? How does it compare to the best season starts in tennis history?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clutch Leaders at 2017 Miami Open</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/04/01/miami-open-clutch-leaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/04/01/miami-open-clutch-leaders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With all but the final round of the 2017 Miami Open decided, it&amp;rsquo;s time to look back at some of the most impressive performances at the second Masters event of the season. Here, we measure &lt;em&gt;impressiveness&lt;/em&gt; by how clutch a player was throughout the event.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A How-To Guide for Tennis Rally Animation</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/03/25/rally-animation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/03/25/rally-animation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With modern tracking data, it is possible to get an almost continuous representation of the locations of both the ball and players during a tennis match. The richness of these data is a huge boon for tennis research but it comes with some challenges too. A lot of my time these days is spent thinking about how best to visualise this information.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Federer-Nadal Rivalry, Has the Federer Backhand Become a Weapon?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/03/17/federer-backhand-trends/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/03/17/federer-backhand-trends/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If tennis fans thought Roger Federer&amp;rsquo;s Australian Open win over Rafael Nadal was a fluke in an otherwise lopsided head-to-head, Federer&amp;rsquo;s devastating victory over Nadal this week at the Indian Wells Masters was a clear message that the AO won&amp;rsquo;t be a one-off for his 2017 season.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Research at the 2017 MIT Sloan Conference Could Mean for Tennis</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/03/11/ssac17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/03/11/ssac17/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week, the sports analytics world descended on Boston for the annual MIT Sloan Sports Analytics Conference (SSAC). Co-founded by Daryl Morey, general manager for the Houston Rockets—a team that, during his tenure, has shaped its identity around its relentless and often innovative use of stats—SSAC has become one of the most popular events for academics and hobbyists to share cutting edge research in sports data science.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Including Futures and Challenger Events in Elo Improve Predictions?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/02/25/elo-error-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/02/25/elo-error-events/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With all of the tiers that exist on the professional tennis circuit, from 10K events up to the Majors, I&amp;rsquo;ve often wondered how tournament tiers should be factored into Elo predictions and whether some events should be excluded entirely. The standard Elo gives players a bigger boost (10% exactly) for wins at Majors but treats wins against similar opponents at any other event the same.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Error Patterns with Elo Predictions</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/02/17/elo-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/02/17/elo-error/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I began to take a &lt;a href=&#34;http://on-the-t.com/2017/02/10/Elo-Court-Pace/&#34;&gt;look at error patterns&lt;/a&gt; with tennis Elo predictions. The question of interest was how does serve advantage influence Elo performance?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elo Prediction Accuracy and Court Pace</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/02/10/elo-court-pace/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/02/10/elo-court-pace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With only two of the top 8 seeds reaching the quarterfinals at the first Grand Slam of the year, the 2017 Australian Open was a trainwreck for most prediction models. Even the Elo forecasting system, one of the most accurate open prediction approaches in tennis, couldn&amp;rsquo;t have anticipated the unusual conditions of this year&amp;rsquo;s Major down under.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How the 2017 Australian Open Men&#39;s Final Was Won</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/30/ao2017-replaying-mens-final/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/30/ao2017-replaying-mens-final/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you are like me, you are spending the day after the final match of the 2017 Australian Open looking for ways to relive the startling 35th meeting of Rafael Nadal and Roger Federer. At the start of the tournament, the chances that Federer would win the title were just 3%; Nadal was an even greater underdog with just 1.5%. Seeing either of them in the final match at Rod Laver Arena wasn&amp;rsquo;t suppose to happen. Yet here we are the day after both men defied the odds and produced what is likely to be one of the most storied moments in tennis history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Most Improved Players at 2017 Australian Open</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/29/ao2017-most-improved/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/29/ao2017-most-improved/</guid>
      <description>Even with the men&amp;rsquo;s final still to come, we can already say that the 2017 Australian Open brought more surprises than anyone expected. As much as we will be focused on the surprise of another Williams sister final and the 35th meeting of Roger Federer and Rafael Nadal, we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t overlook the less familiar names that impressed us at the first Slam of the season.
Since it is sometimes hard to look back at two weeks of matchplay and pick out the performances that surprised us most, I was thinking how you might try to put a number to &amp;ldquo;improvement&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nadal is More Predictable on Serve Under Pressure</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/28/ao2017-nadal-serve-predictability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/28/ao2017-nadal-serve-predictability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are looking forward to two classic finals in the men&amp;rsquo;s and women&amp;rsquo;s events at this year&amp;rsquo;s Australian Open. The men&amp;rsquo;s matchup will be the 35th meeting of Rafael Nadal and Roger Federer and their 22nd meeting in a tournament final.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shot Quality Review of the Federer Wawrinka AO2017 Semifinal</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/27/ao2017-federer-warinka/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/27/ao2017-federer-warinka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night, the first of the two men&amp;rsquo;s semifinals was played on Rod Laver Arena. By the end of the second set, it looked like it was going to be a short night for the Australia Day crowd. Then Stan Wawrinka&amp;rsquo;s first break in the fourth game of the third set changed everything.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rally Lengths are Down at the Australian Open</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/26/ao2017-rally-lengths/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/26/ao2017-rally-lengths/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the prospect of a Rafael Nadal and Roger Federer final at this year&amp;rsquo;s Australian Open, many are probably wondering if we are in store for the relatively speedy match when they last played here in 2014 or an epic more like their four-hour plus semifinal at the 2012 AO. There hasn&amp;rsquo;t been much that is predictable about this year&amp;rsquo;s Australian Open. One had to be clairvoyant to have picked a Nadal-Federer final (if that turns out to be what we get) let alone how long such a meeting could last.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attacking Play Wins Out at AO2017</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/25/ao2017-women-attacking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/25/ao2017-women-attacking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This year&amp;rsquo;s Australian Open has turned many of the game&amp;rsquo;s norms on its head. While the dust is still settling from the upsets of a number of the favorites in the first week, we are starting to see how some of the surprises for the title have been so successful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AO 2017 Quarterfinalist Shot Quality</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/24/ao2017-shot-quality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/24/ao2017-shot-quality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The second week of a Major always reminds us what a high-level of shot making we are lucky to witness in the current era of tennis. Yet, even among the top players we know there is variation in the &lt;em&gt;quality of shot&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AO 2017 Most Unpredictable?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/23/ao2017-unpredictable/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/23/ao2017-unpredictable/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When defending champion Novak Djokovic went out in the second round to qualifier Denis Istomin, we all had to be thinking that it was the most surprising match result we were likely to see at the 2017 Australian Open. Then Day 7 happened.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AO 2017 Nadal Monfils R16</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/22/ao2017-nadal-monfils/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/22/ao2017-nadal-monfils/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I write, Andy Murray and Mischa Zverev are battling for a place in the quarterfinals in what has the makings of an epic. Another match we all hope will deliver the same excitement is Rafael Nadal and Gael Monfils&#39; meeting on Monday, in the marquee night match on Rod Laver Arena.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AO 2017 Day 5 Top Contenders</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/20/ao2017-top10-day5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/20/ao2017-top10-day5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The clouds that have rolled in over Melbourne Park on Day 5 of the 2017 Australian Open seem to be a reminder of the strange events the day before. The ousting of Novak Djokovic by Denis Istomin and Aga Radwanska by Mirjana Lucic-Baroni made Day 4 one of the most shocking of the event so far.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AO 2017 Day 2 Review In Four Match Charts</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/18/ao-day2-charts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/18/ao-day2-charts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There were fewer upsets and escapes on Day 2 of the 2017 Australian Open, but still plenty of excitement. Below you can find the point-by-point win prediction charts for four of the most exciting matches of the day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AO2017 Day 1 Review In Four Match Charts</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/17/ao2017-top4-day1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/17/ao2017-top4-day1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first half of the draw is done and we&amp;rsquo;ve already seen a number of surprises. In this post, Tennis Australia&amp;rsquo;s GIG has put together win probability charts to capture the ebbs and flows of 4 of the most contested matches on Day 1.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AO 2017 Luck of the Draw</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/15/ao2017-luck-of-draw/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/15/ao2017-luck-of-draw/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the curious things about tennis is that every seeded player&amp;rsquo;s path to the title is different. When the champions are hoisting a tournament trophy over their heads, we largely ignore the role that luck might have played in their victory. But should it be ignored? And how much of a role does luck play anyway?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AO Women&#39;s Predictions</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/14/ao-womens-predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/14/ao-womens-predictions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the release of the 2017 Australian Open draw yesterday, the tennis world will be spending the weekend mulling over the implications of where the seeds and dark horses of the event have landed. To help navigate these discussions, the Game Insight Group is breaking down the probabilities of the likely outcomes of the tournament, round by round.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AO Men&#39;s Predictions</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/13/ao-mens-predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/13/ao-mens-predictions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2017 Australian Open draw is out. To put some numbers to the prospects for the 128 players on each side of the draw who will make their bid for the title, Tennis Australia Game Insight Group has put together predictions for the tournament outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AO Leaderboard - Work</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/07/aoleaderboard-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/01/07/aoleaderboard-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first week of the 2017 tennis season saw the debut of many of the world&amp;rsquo;s best players. One of the players that tennis fans will be expecting the most from is the recently &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.news.com.au/sport/tennis/british-tennis-star-andy-murray-knighted-after-amazing-season/news-story/6191b34118355421ef96820aa18c2bdc&#34;&gt;knighted Sir Andy Murray&lt;/a&gt;. Not just because of the knighthood but because of last year&amp;rsquo;s miraculous season that propelled that honour and saw Murray do the impossible: take the World No. 1 ranking from Novak Djokovic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AO Leaderboard - Women&#39;s Distances</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/12/30/aoleaderboard-womens-distances/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/12/30/aoleaderboard-womens-distances/</guid>
      <description>In my last post, I took a look at the distances covered in matches and points for male players. The stats from Tennis Australia&amp;rsquo;s Game Insight Group showed that men at the Australian Open travel 2 to 3 miles per match and the big servers of the game tend to travel the least of all players.
But what about the women&amp;rsquo;s tour? What are the typical distances for them and who are the biggest movers?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AO Leaderboard - Men&#39;s Distances</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/12/24/aoleaderboard-mens-distances/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/12/24/aoleaderboard-mens-distances/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During a tennis match broadcast you will sometimes see a stat on the distances run by players. But we rarely get a look at the distances run over all matches in a tournament or a season, numbers that could tell us what kinds of distances are typical at the elite level and what are extreme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AO Leaderboard - Serve Plus 1 Stroke</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/12/17/aoleaderboard-forehand-backhand-serve1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/12/17/aoleaderboard-forehand-backhand-serve1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the ways that the men&amp;rsquo;s and women&amp;rsquo;s games differ the most is the serve. While previous posts on this site have shown that the speeds of men&amp;rsquo;s and women&amp;rsquo;s groundstrokes are actually &lt;a href=&#34;http://on-the-t.com/2016/11/26/AOLeaderboard-Forehand-Speed/&#34;&gt;fairly comparable&lt;/a&gt;, the men separate themselves by far on serve. On hard court, the average first serve for men is 115 mph and the average first serve for women is 99 mph.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AO Leaderboard - Winning Rallies</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/12/10/aoleaderboard-rally-winners/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/12/10/aoleaderboard-rally-winners/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When we think of the best ralliers in the game, we are thinking of the players who not only have a penchant for extended points but also win those points. While tournaments will sometimes tell us about typical rally lengths, we don&amp;rsquo;t usually know how a player&amp;rsquo;s chances of winning a point vary with rally length. In this post, I look into this question using Australian Open statistics provided by the Game Insight Group of Tennis Australia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AO Leaderboard - Rally Lengths</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/12/03/aoleaderboard-rally-lengths/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/12/03/aoleaderboard-rally-lengths/</guid>
      <description>Rally lengths are a useful measure for differentiating styles of play. Players who tend to keep points to a few shots would be expected to be dominant on serve and more willing to go to net. Players who tend to grind out extended rallies would tend to be the baseliners whose best weapons are their groundstrokes and endurance.
Some analysts have characterised the professional game as first strike tennis, because the majority of points are 4 shots or fewer (counting the serve).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AO Leaderboard - Forehand Speeds</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/11/26/aoleaderboard-forehand-speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/11/26/aoleaderboard-forehand-speed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s Australian Open Leaderboard series returns to groundstroke speeds. Below, are charts showing speed at impact (in mph) for groundstroke forehands (shots landing within 3 meters of the baseline) observed at the 2014 to 2016 AO.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AO Leaderboard - Reaction Time</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/11/19/aoleaderboard-reaction-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/11/19/aoleaderboard-reaction-time/</guid>
      <description>In my last post I discussed the idea of return pressure and suggested that it could be measured by looking at the amount of time a receiver gives the server to prepare for their second shot. Players who exert more pressure with their return of serve are expected to get a quicker jump on the ball and make a more powerful shot inside the baseline.
In this post I want to focus on one part of that equation, the quick jump, by looking at reaction times on the serve return.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AO Leaderboard - Return Pressure</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/11/12/aoleaderboard-return-pressure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/11/12/aoleaderboard-return-pressure/</guid>
      <description>The tennis world is gearing up for the ATP World Tour Finals, where 8 of the best male players will vie for the final major title of 2016. One of the things that could be decisive in who advances to the semifinals is the pressure of the return. Here, when I refer to return pressure, I am thinking of the kind of player who jumps on the serve and makes an attacking shot that gives the server little time to react.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AO Leaderboard - Net Clearance</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/11/05/aoleaderboard-line-hitting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/11/05/aoleaderboard-line-hitting/</guid>
      <description>The Masters in Bercy continues concerns over Novak Djokovic&amp;rsquo;s form going into the Tour Finals. With the loss to Marin Cilic in Paris and Andy Murray one win away from taking the World No. 1 spot, the 2016 season has raised many questions about Djokovic&amp;rsquo;s performance. While we see the indicators of a slump from his win record, we can&amp;rsquo;t know whether and how his game has actually changed— has he lost effectiveness on serve?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AO Leaderboard - Line Hitting</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/10/29/aoleaderboard-line-hitting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/10/29/aoleaderboard-line-hitting/</guid>
      <description>This week continues the rollout of a collection of new statistics describing the quality of shots in tennis. Last week began with a look at groundstroke speeds, focusing on the backhand. This week we turn to the accuracy of groundstrokes and look specifically at how frequently shots land close to the line.
Whether a ball lands close to a line is obviously a subjective call. In the summaries that follow, I will use 3 ball lengths (approximately 21 cm) as &amp;ldquo;close&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AO Leaderboard - Backhand Speeds</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/10/22/aoleaderboard-backhand-speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/10/22/aoleaderboard-backhand-speed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hard to believe that it is only a few months before the start of the 2017 ATP and WTA seasons. Preparations for the 2017 AO in Melbourne are already in high gear. There will be a lot of developments you can expect to see come January, including some new stats using Hawk-Eye ball and player tracking data. These stats were developed by Tennis Australia&amp;rsquo;s Game Insight Group— a team of scientists TA has brought together to advance the use of analytics in tennis. As a data scientist for the GIG, I wanted to preview these developments and some of the things we are learning from tracking data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clutch Edge at the 2016 U.S. Open</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/10/14/clutch-differentials/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/10/14/clutch-differentials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the past few posts, I have been applying a new metric &lt;em&gt;clutch averages&lt;/em&gt; to the men&amp;rsquo;s and women&amp;rsquo;s singles matches at the 2016 U.S. Open. The purpose of these averages is to focus on how players tend to perform on the most important points in a match. In this way, these stats can help us to find out which players win the majority of the most important points? And which players are most and least affected by the scoreline?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clutch Review of the ATP at the 2016 U.S. Open</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/10/07/us-open-men-clutch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/10/07/us-open-men-clutch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&#34;http://on-the-t.com/2016/09/23/US-Open-Women-Clutch/&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt; took us back to the U.S. Open and reviewed the most and least clutch players on the WTA. This week I do the same review for the men. As before, the clutch performance represented here is the summary of the most important points won on serve (Figure 1) and return (Figure 2). These summaries include big points like break points, of course, but also factors in other important points &amp;ndash; like tiebreak points or 30-all situations late in a set. In each case, the score situation is weighed by its relative importance, which is its expected influence on a win or loss.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clutch Review of the WTA at the 2016 U.S. Open</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/09/23/us-open-women-clutch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/09/23/us-open-women-clutch/</guid>
      <description>The 2016 U.S. Open might now be a faint memory of the news cycle but there are still plenty of stories about player performance that were never told. This week, I have been digging into the point-by-point data from this year&amp;rsquo;s matches at Flushing to find out how players handled the biggest moments of the tournament.
I have talked before about how we can use a point&amp;rsquo;s importance to identify who are the most clutch performers in the sport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizations of Day 14 at the 2016 U.S. Open</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/09/12/us-open-mens-final-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/09/12/us-open-mens-final-review/</guid>
      <description>The final day of the 2016 U.S. Open brought us the 26th meeting of Novak Djokovic and Stan Wawrinka. Djokovic has built up such a win record in recent years that, even at the final stage of a Grand Slam against as formidable an opponent as World No. 3 Stan Wawrinka, he was still the favorite by far. FiveThirtyEight predictions gave the World No. 1 an 88% chance of winning his 13th Major title.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizations of Day 13 at the 2016 U.S. Open</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/09/11/us-open-womens-final-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/09/11/us-open-womens-final-review/</guid>
      <description>After three sets on a muggy Saturday in New York, Angelique Kerber defeated Karolina Pliskova to win her first U.S. Open Major and her second Grand Slam title of the year. Kerber had already secured the World No. 1 rank in getting to the finals, after Williams defeat to Pliskova in the semifinal. Pliskova was on a terrifying run, taking out both Williams sisters to get her spot in the final.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizations of Day 12 at the 2016 U.S. Open</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/09/10/us-open-mens-semifinal-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/09/10/us-open-mens-semifinal-review/</guid>
      <description>After a day of women&amp;rsquo;s semifinals that saw the exit and dethroning of World No. 1 Serena Williams, the favorites in the men&amp;rsquo;s semifinals had to be on guard when they stepped onto court today. The first match of the day pitted a fresh Novak Djokovic against showman and crowd favorite Gael Monfils. The day was be closed out by the matchup of Kei Nishikori and Stan Wawrinka. Both matches were hard-fought and delivered a packed highlight reel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizations of Day 11 at the 2016 U.S. Open</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/09/09/us-open-womens-semifinal-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/09/09/us-open-womens-semifinal-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The shocks keep coming at the U.S. Open. After Kei Nishikori&amp;rsquo;s surprising upset of Andy Murray in the quarterfinals of Day 10, Day 11 brought us another massive upset. Today it was Serena Williams&#39; turn to exit the tournament, as Karolina Pliskova denied her a 23rd major title. After the loss to Roberta Vinci at the 2015 U.S. Open, this makes for back-to-back disappointments for Williams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizations of Day 10 at the 2016 U.S. Open</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/09/08/us-open-round5-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/09/08/us-open-round5-review/</guid>
      <description>Today wrapped up the last half of the men&amp;rsquo;s and women&amp;rsquo;s quarterfinals of the 2016 U.S. Open. Two of the favorites for the title—Serena Williams and Andy Murray—were on center stage. Serena Williams was tested by a determined Simona Halep but would eventually make it through. Andy Murray, on the other hand, would fall in 5 to Japanese No 1. Kei Nishikori. Here are visual summaries of how those and the two other quarterfinal matches of the day were decided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizations of Day 9 at the 2016 U.S. Open</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/09/07/us-open-round5-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/09/07/us-open-round5-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day 9 brought us the first half of the quarterfinals of the 2016 U.S. Open. It was a day when the favorites were in top-form, closing out all of their matches in swift fashion. Here we review how both the two women&amp;rsquo;s and two men&amp;rsquo;s quarterfinal matches of the day were won.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizations of the First Day of Round 4 at the 2016 U.S. Open</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/09/05/us-open-round4-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/09/05/us-open-round4-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Day 7, the last day of week 1 at the 2016 U.S. Open, saw the losses of two Americans (Keys and Sock), the upset of a favorite for the men&amp;rsquo;s title (Nadal), and the resurgence of a former World No. 1 (Wozniacki). Below are the point-by-point win prediction charts for 4 of the most interesting wins in the first half of Round 4.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizations of the First Day of Round 3 at the 2016 U.S. Open</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/09/03/us-open-round3-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/09/03/us-open-round3-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are nearing the end of the first day of Round 3 and the surprises continue. There were some big wins and near big losses for the players at Flushing today. In this post, I will look at the point-by-point predictions for 5 of the day&amp;rsquo;s tightest matches. By looking over the charts of the match-in-progress can help us appreciate how a match was won and what some of the most shocking wins of the day were.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizations of the Final Day of Round 2 at the 2016 U.S. Open</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/09/02/us-open-round2-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/09/02/us-open-round2-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The final day of Round 2 at the 2016 U.S. Open brought some more upsets and nail-biting battles. I have selected 6 of the most contested matches of the day and created point-by-point prediction charts to track the ebbs and flows of each. The expectations for each match are based on &lt;a href=&#34;http://projects.fivethirtyeight.com/2016-us-open-tennis-predictions/mens/&#34;&gt;player Elo ratings&lt;/a&gt;. These ratings tells us how capable a player should be of winning a match against their drawn opponent if both players are playing to their expected ability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importance Breakdown of Harrison&#39;s 2016 U.S. Open Upset of Milos Raonic</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/09/01/us-open-harrison-raonic-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/09/01/us-open-harrison-raonic-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the first day of Round 2 of the 2016 U.S. Open, an American served up what could turn out to be one of the biggest upsets of the tournament. Ryan Harrison, ranked 220 in the world and known mostly for a &lt;a href=&#34;http://fivethirtyeight.com/datalab/at-wimbledon-ryan-harrison-suffers-again-from-his-bad-luck-of-the-draw/&#34;&gt;streak of unlucky draws&lt;/a&gt; at Grand Slams, defeated huge-hitting World No. 6 Milos Raonic 6-7 (4), 7-5, 7-5, 6-1.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importance Breakdown of Fritz-Sock 2016 U.S. Open Match</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/08/31/us-open-fritz-sock-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/08/31/us-open-fritz-sock-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have gotten through the first round and already the 2016 U.S. Open has given us a number of epics. One of those was the all-American matchup of Jack Sock and Taylor Fritz, a match that was highlighted in the clutch preview &lt;a href=&#34;http://on-the-t.com/2016/08/29/US-Open-Mens-First-Round-Preview/&#34;&gt;on this blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>US Open Men&#39;s First Round Clutch Preview</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/08/29/us-open-mens-first-round-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/08/29/us-open-mens-first-round-preview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The first round of the main draw of the 2016 US Open begins today. If you are like me you have spent a good part of the weekend digesting the draw and making predictions about which matches could be the most interesting to come out of Flushing Meadows. In this post, I want to highlight a few of the matches that stood out to me. In doing so, I also want to introduce a new way of looking at recent form with something I call &lt;strong&gt;clutch averaging&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>US Open Women&#39;s First Round Clutch Preview</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/08/29/us-open-womens-first-round-preview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/08/29/us-open-womens-first-round-preview/</guid>
      <description>This post continues on my first round preview for the 2016 US Open Championships. Having already taken a dip into the men&amp;rsquo;s draw, let&amp;rsquo;s now take a look at some of the most interesting of the women&amp;rsquo;s matches in the days ahead.
As with the men&amp;rsquo;s preview, I have selected among matches of players who have some match history and have reported. For each match, clutch summary statistics of the players&#39; last meeting and most recent result are shown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charting Shots Over Expectations</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/08/20/charting-shots-over-expectations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/08/20/charting-shots-over-expectations/</guid>
      <description>In statistics, an expectation is a way to quantify what is typical or likely. And, when we compare what actually happened against what was expected, we have a way to judge how surprised or unimpressed we should be.
Despite their usefulness, you are as likely to see a probabilistic expectation in tennis as you are a floral pattern at Wimbledon. Mainstream tennis stats only report what happened, not what was likely to happen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charting Serve Locations</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/08/18/charting-serve-locations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/08/18/charting-serve-locations/</guid>
      <description>One of the many things I miss after the dissolution of Bill Simmons&#39; sports blog Grantland is Kirk Goldsberry&amp;rsquo;s NBA shot charts. The classic version of the Goldsberry shot chart is a plot of hexagonal bins showing the locations and frequency of where a player takes shots overlaid onto a representation of the basketball court. Combined with heavy annotation and a lot of style, the charts are both effective at communicating shot tendencies and a pure pleasure to read (an example for Steph Curry is shown to the right).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klaassen &amp; Magnus&#39;s 22 Myths of Tennis - Myth 22</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/08/06/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/08/06/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-22/</guid>
      <description>While most of the sports world has had been focused on the start of the summer Olympics this week, a small group of diehard sports statisticians were attending the Joint Statistical Meetings in Chicago and catching up with recent advances in sports analytics. During my time there, I was fortunate to participate in a panel entitled &amp;ldquo;Harnessing the Extraordinary Power of Statistics in Sports&amp;rdquo;. The panel was organized by Michael Lopez, of Skidmore College and twitter fame @StatsByLopez, and chaired by Michael Schuckers at St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klaassen &amp; Magnus&#39;s 22 Myths of Tennis - Myth 21</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/07/30/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/07/30/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-21/</guid>
      <description>July has been a stellar month for British player Johanna Konta. After defeating one of her idols, Venus Williams, to win a Premier title at Stanford, Konta will play today for a spot in the semifinal of the Rogers Cup.
Embed from Getty Images This month, Konta just can&amp;rsquo;t seem to lose. When players hit a streak like Konta has, it can sometime seem like winning becomes inevitable, as if with each win added to their record the next win becomes even more likely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klaassen &amp; Magnus&#39;s 22 Myths of Tennis - Myth 20</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/07/23/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/07/23/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-20/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As we near the end of our look back at the 22 tennis myths of Klaassen and Magnus, we find less novelty in the ideas. Rather than spend too much time covering old ground, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to keep things interesting by looking at each topic in a new way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klaassen &amp; Magnus&#39;s 22 Myths of Tennis - Myth 19</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/07/16/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/07/16/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2016 Wimbledon Championships brought us a number of stories and memorable matches. But, with the third round exit of Novak Djokovic, we &lt;em&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; get to see a semifinal between Djokovic and Federer. We will have to wait a few more weeks for the arrival of the US Open for the next opportunity to see if Federer can still test Djokovic on a slam stage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klaassen &amp; Magnus&#39;s 22 Myths of Tennis - Myth 18</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/07/08/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/07/08/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-18/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a sad day for Federer fans. After a glorious comeback from two sets down in the quarterfinals, Federer&amp;rsquo;s bid for an eighth Wimbledon title was cut short by big-serving Milos Raonic on Friday.
Like most close matches, the margins separating Federer and Raonic were tiny. With 70% of points won on serve and 29% of points won on return, Federer was just one percentage point behind the Canadian star on both skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klaassen &amp; Magnus&#39;s 22 Myths of Tennis - Myth 17</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/07/02/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/07/02/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-17/</guid>
      <description>One of the matches we can look forward to—rain or shine—on Day 6 of the Wimbledon Championships is World No. 2 Andy Murray against Aussie John Millman. Murray&amp;rsquo;s run at Wimbledon is an especially interesting one because it is the first Grand Slam since Murray&amp;rsquo;s reunion with legend coach Ivan Lendl. The on-again off-again partnership provides an interesting natural experiment of the &amp;ldquo;coach effect&amp;rdquo; and gives us one more reason to look back at one of my favorite tennis memes of all time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klaassen &amp; Magnus&#39;s 22 Myths of Tennis - Myth 16</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/06/25/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/06/25/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Britain&amp;rsquo;s decision to Brexit will inevitably make for an unusual backdrop at the 2016 Wimbledon, which gets underway this weekend. But with a packed draw and stadium roofs to combat uncooperative weather, we can still expect the next two weeks to bring us some unforgettable matches and headline worthy moments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klaassen &amp; Magnus&#39;s 22 Myths of Tennis - Myth 15</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/06/17/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/06/17/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-15/</guid>
      <description>Choking is one of the most fascinating phenomena in sport. 2016 provided us with a spectacular example of a choke when Jordan Spieth made a quadruple-bogey on hole 12 of the Augusta Masters, setting into motion the loss of a near-certain win on the final day on those hallowed links.
Although we may not ever see a meltdown of that magnitude again for years to come, it still serves as a reminder of the role of pressure in competition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klaassen &amp; Magnus&#39;s 22 Myths of Tennis - Myth 14</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/06/10/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/06/10/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last weekend, when the sun finally shone down on Philippe Chatrier, we witnessed two very different but equally fascinating storylines emerge. On the women&amp;rsquo;s side, twenty-two year old Garbiñe Muguruza, a rising star with only one previous appearance in a Grand Slam final, thwarted Serena Williams&#39; third bid at her twenty-second title to her first major win.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klaassen &amp; Magnus&#39;s 22 Myths of Tennis - Myth 13</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/06/04/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/06/04/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Zebra prints and back-to-back matches haven&amp;rsquo;t been the only strange things to appear at this year&amp;rsquo;s French Open. The washout that has been a catastrophe for the 2016 Roland Garros schedule has created a myriad of unusual pressures and demands for the players (and a few of them have been vocal about their dislike of the situation). As a consequence of all this, player adaptability and grit have taken higher places in the list of skills needed to advance to the next round than would be the case in drier conditions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klaassen &amp; Magnus&#39;s 22 Myths of Tennis - Myth 12</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/05/21/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/05/21/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this week&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.si.com/si-beyond-the-baseline-tennis-podcast&#34;&gt;Beyond the Baseline&lt;/a&gt; preview to the French Open, Jon Wertheim called the women&amp;rsquo;s draw from spot 2 down &amp;ldquo;all over the place&amp;rdquo;. With only 2 2016 clay court titles among the top 4 seeds on the women&amp;rsquo;s side and Serena Williams without a major title since last year&amp;rsquo;s Wimbledon, it&amp;rsquo;s looking like anyone&amp;rsquo;s guess over which WTA player will walk away with the Roland Garros title in two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klaassen &amp; Magnus&#39;s 22 Myths of Tennis - Myth 11</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/05/14/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/05/14/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-11/</guid>
      <description>After Novak Djokovic&amp;rsquo;s surprising early exit last month at the Monte Carlo Masters tournament, this week it was Roger Federer&amp;rsquo;s turn. His first clay court event since Monte Carlo was brought to a decisive halt when he lost to Dominic Thiem in the third round at the Rome Masters.
Now any player can have an off day, especially when coming back from injury. But when it happens to the best players in the game, it&amp;rsquo;s often the source of alarm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klaassen &amp; Magnus&#39;s 22 Myths of Tennis - Myth 10</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/05/08/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/05/08/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-10/</guid>
      <description>After two close semifinals, World No. 2 Andy Murray is set to defend his Madrid Masters title against top seed Novak Djokovic. The fact that the two go into the match at the top of the ATP rankings leaderboard suggests that we are in store for a quality match, with Djokovic being the perennial favorite.
But what exactly does the difference of one position in ranking really tell us about the expected quality of play?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klaassen &amp; Magnus&#39;s 22 Myths of Tennis - Myth 9</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/05/01/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/05/01/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After Alexander Zverev took the first set in 6-4 against Dominic Thiem at Saturday&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.atpworldtour.com/en/news/thiem-kohlschreiber-munich-2016-saturday&#34;&gt;BMW Open semifinal&lt;/a&gt;, it looked like he was on track to stop the Austrian&amp;rsquo;s 29th ATP singles win this season. But the tables quickly turned and after taking the second sets in 6-2 and 6-3, Thiem ultimately prevailed, securing a spot in the final against Philipp Kohlschreiber.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klaassen &amp; Magnus&#39;s 22 Myths of Tennis - Myth 8</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/04/24/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/04/24/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-8/</guid>
      <description>The break-heavy clay court season continued in the men&amp;rsquo;s semifinal match where World No. 5 Rafael Nadal faced-off against 31st-ranked Fabio Fognini. There were a total of 8 breaks in the match, 4 in each set. There were also two of the most frustrating of break phenomena, the back-to-back break. The first came in the fifth game of the first set, when Fognini broke Nadal&amp;rsquo;s serve and put himself on the scoreboard for the first time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klaassen &amp; Magnus&#39;s 22 Myths of Tennis - Myth 7</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/04/19/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/04/19/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-7/</guid>
      <description>With the second round exit of Novak Djokovic and the quarterfinal loss of Roger Federer, the finals of the 2016 Monte Carlo Masters brought us a pairing we might not have expected on Day 1, but a thrilling one nonetheless. The first two sets between Rafael Nadal and Gael Monfils on Sunday were as tightly contested as the fans that withstood a rainy morning in Monaco could have hoped for. Each player exchanged a 7-5 win, battling through multiple long rallies and over two hours of matchplay to reach the third deciding set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klaassen &amp; Magnus&#39;s 22 Myths of Tennis - Myth 6</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/04/09/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/04/09/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-6/</guid>
      <description>Raymond Moore&amp;rsquo;s display of sexism at this year&amp;rsquo;s BNP Paribas Open put a more intense spotlight on gender equality in tennis than any of us were expecting. The processing of his statements and resignation as tournament director prompted some insightful perspective-taking by former and current players. At the same time, it also encouraged more of the same old pitting of the WTA and ATP tours against each other.
With this backdrop in mind, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but cringe when I read myth 6 of Klaasseen and Magnus: &amp;lsquo;the probability that the service is in is the same in men&amp;rsquo;s and women&amp;rsquo;s singles&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klaassen &amp; Magnus&#39;s 22 Myths of Tennis - Myth 5</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/04/04/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/04/04/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-5/</guid>
      <description>The 5th myth in Klaassen and Magnus&amp;rsquo;s examination of some of the most common beliefs in tennis puts point importance at center stage once again. With myth 5, K&amp;amp;M ask if there is any truth to the idea that all points in tennis are equally important.
Of all of the 22 beliefs that K&amp;amp;M consider in Analyzing Wimbledon this is the one that probably has the least traction in the tennis community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klaassen &amp; Magnus&#39;s 22 Myths of Tennis - Myth 4</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/03/20/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/03/20/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The fourth myth in the countdown of Klaassen and Magnus&amp;rsquo;s 22 myths of tennis is &lt;em&gt;the myth of the seventh game&lt;/em&gt;. Listen to enough tennis commentary or read through enough posts on tennis forums and you are bound to come across the idea that the seventh game is the most important game in the set.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tennis Enters the Big Leagues of Sports Analytics</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/03/15/tennis-enters-the-big-leagures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/03/15/tennis-enters-the-big-leagures/</guid>
      <description>Last week many of the sports world&amp;rsquo;s most innovative number crunchers converged in Boston at the MIT Sloan Analytics Conference. The 10th anniversary of the two-day nerd fest attracted 3,900 attendees and some of the heaviest hitters in sports stats, including Bill James, Nate Silver, and Mike Zarren.
One of the traditional features of Sloan is the research competition. In true sporting fashion, this is a multi-stage, single-elimination tournament that pits the top research innovations in sports analytics against each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klaassen &amp; Magnus&#39;s 22 Myths of Tennis - Myth 3</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/03/05/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/03/05/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-3/</guid>
      <description>The next myth in our look back at Klaassen and Magnus&amp;rsquo;s takedown of 22 tennis myths is Myth 3. This myth concerns the importance of points and whether each point is equally important to the server and returner.
Myth 3: &amp;ldquo;Every point (game, set) is equally important to both players&amp;rdquo; In Analyzing Wimbledon Klaassen and Magnus make the logically argument that a point is always equally important to the server and receiver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klaassen &amp; Magnus&#39;s 22 Myths of Tennis - Myth 2</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/02/24/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/02/24/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis2/</guid>
      <description>The second myth addressed in Klaassen and Magnus&amp;rsquo;s instant classic of tennis analysis, Analyzing Wimbledon, is the myth of serving first in a match.
Myth 2: &amp;ldquo;Is there an advantage to serve first in a set?&amp;rdquo; The coin toss is one of those pre-match rituals that many of us fast-forward through. If you can recall any occasion when you have stopped to watch the coin toss, there is a very good chance that the player who won the toss opted to serve.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Klaassen &amp; Magnus&#39;s 22 Myths of Tennis - Myth 1</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/02/14/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/02/14/klaassen-magnus-hypothesis-1/</guid>
      <description>Books on tennis statistics are as rare as black swans. So I take notice whenever one appears.
One of the most recent of these scarce creatures is Franc Klaassen and Jan Magnus&amp;rsquo;s Analyzing Wimbledon. Despite having primary appointments in economic departments, Klaassen and Magnus have produced some of the most scholarly mathematical papers on tennis. Analyzing Wimbledon is a compilation of the findings that have come out of their long partnership, synthesized into a list of 22 myths of tennis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing a GUI for the Match Charting Project</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/02/07/match-charting-gui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/02/07/match-charting-gui/</guid>
      <description>We are just a little more than a month into the 2016 tennis season. With 10 months of matches, 3 Grand Slams, and the Rio Olympics ahead of us; there is plenty to look forward to.
Still, every year the data the sport gathers and makes available to the public is way too basic. You know those end-of-match summaries with the simple counts of first serve points, second serve points, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AO 2016 Retrospective</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2016/02/01/ao-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2016/02/01/ao-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend we closed the chapter on the first Grand Slam of 2016. As all our  news feeds overflowed with the photos of the tournament champions Novak Djokovic and first-time major winner, Angelique Kerber, in the hours that followed their victories, each snapshot was a reminder of how much can happen in just two weeks time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying Clutch Performance</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2015/12/27/quantifying-clutch-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2015/12/27/quantifying-clutch-performance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just as some people are unusually good at finding the perfect gift to put under the Christmas tree, some tennis players are unusually good at pulling out a win when it matters most. This is the quintessential characteristic of the &amp;ldquo;clutch player&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Take on the Best Season Debate</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2015/11/28/best-season-debate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2015/11/28/best-season-debate/</guid>
      <description>After solidifying a career best season with the win of the ATP Tour Finals, definitive World No. 1 Novak Djokovic set the tennis world chattering about where his 2015 season stood in the history of best tennis seasons. It is fitting for these discussions that Djokovic&amp;rsquo;s last win of 2015 was over Roger Federer, the current World No. 3 whose achievements in the mid 2000s have often been argued to be some of the greatest in the Open Era.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WAR for All Seasons</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2015/11/14/war-for-all-seasons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2015/11/14/war-for-all-seasons/</guid>
      <description>Last week I asked whether WAR, a comprehensive statistic of player value, has a place in tennis. Although WAR was developed for and has been primarily used in team sports to estimate a player&amp;rsquo;s contribution to team wins, its potential applications are much broader. WAR, in its most general sense, is about giving perspective to a player&amp;rsquo;s performance by comparing the outcomes of a player&amp;rsquo;s outings to a common standard: the replacement player.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial Thoughts on Developing WAR for Tennis</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2015/11/07/developing-war-for-tennis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2015/11/07/developing-war-for-tennis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If, based on the title of this post, you were expecting some kind of jingoistic fantasy of tennis players armed with bazookas, you were mistaken. This post isn&amp;rsquo;t about that kind of war (as much as &lt;em&gt;ESPN&lt;/em&gt; might be interested in such a gladiatorial venture); it&amp;rsquo;s about the sabermetric kind of WAR.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Future of Tennis Data - A Conversation with Edoardo Salvati</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2015/11/02/conversation-with-edoardo-salvati/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2015/11/02/conversation-with-edoardo-salvati/</guid>
      <description>Earlier this week, FiveThirtyEight writer Oliver Roeder published an article entitled &amp;ldquo;Can An Astrophysicist Change The Way We Watch Sports?&amp;quot; The piece documents the efforts of Matt Ginsberg (the astrophysicist in question) to develop a system for real-time predictions of shot-making for the NBA and, at the same time, raises a number of broad questions about the future of advanced analytics in sports and sports broadcasting. One of the questions that most intrigued me is whether, as the title of the article suggests, any one person can &amp;ldquo;revolutionize&amp;rdquo; how we experience sports?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Break Points are More Decisive for WTA</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2015/10/24/breakpoints-more-decisive-for-wta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2015/10/24/breakpoints-more-decisive-for-wta/</guid>
      <description>Last week I openly admitted to a new obsession with break points, which has lead me down a path of investigations to try to understand the role of break points for winning in tennis. One product to come out of this is the concept of break point decisiveness, which I define as the percentage of matches in which the winner also won more break points than the loser. My last post showed that break point decisiveness ranges from 87 to 91% for the ATP, depending on which surface and match format (best of 3 or best of 5) is being played.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Decisive are Break Points?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2015/10/17/how-decisive-are-breakpoints/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2015/10/17/how-decisive-are-breakpoints/</guid>
      <description>As part of the work I have been doing on the Pythagorean model for wins in tennis, I have—in-between MLB playoffs and the Shanghai Masters, in any case—been thinking a lot about break points lately.
We all know break points are important. If a player doesn&amp;rsquo;t edge out his or her opponent&amp;rsquo;s break points won in a set, the set (and ultimately the match) will have to be decided in a tiebreak or, when a tiebreak isn&amp;rsquo;t in place, a match could go on ad infinitum as some of us thought might happen when big servers Isner and Mahut butted heads in the 2010 Wimbledon first round.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Djokovic Streaky But No DiMaggio</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2015/10/10/djokovic-streaky-but-no-dimaggio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2015/10/10/djokovic-streaky-but-no-dimaggio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you have been following the ATP Tour&amp;rsquo;s China Open this week, you have probably seen references to Novak Djokovic&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.foxsports.com/tennis/story/rafael-nadal-ana-ivanovic-sara-errani-china-open-tennis-quarterfinals-100915&#34;&gt;winning streak&lt;/a&gt;. He will enter the final against long-time rival Rafael Nadal with a 28-0 record over 6 total appearances at the Beijing 500.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Women as Pythagorean as Men in Tennis?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2015/10/03/are-women-as-pythagorean-as-men/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2015/10/03/are-women-as-pythagorean-as-men/</guid>
      <description>Last week, based on work presented at the 2015 NESSIS, I wrote about an extension of Pythagorean Expectation to tennis, which showed that break point conversion has a strikingly similar ability to predict match wins in tennis as runs predict team wins in baseball. The Pythagorean analyses were based only on the men&amp;rsquo;s tour. In this post, thanks to match statistics published by Jeff Sackmann of Tennis Abstract, I will examine the existence of a Pythagorean formula for women&amp;rsquo;s tennis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting Clutch into Wins - A Pythagorean Model for Tennis</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2015/09/26/converting-clutch-into-wins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2015/09/26/converting-clutch-into-wins/</guid>
      <description>In the short life of this blog, I have, on several occasions, complained about the lack of analytics in tennis. But what evidence is there to back up this view? One place to start to unpack the state of analytics in tennis is by comparison to other major sports that are at the forefront of the analytics revolution. In this article I want to discuss one gap that such a comparison reveals— the lack of metrics for win expectation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charting the Match Charting Project</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2015/09/19/charting-match-charting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2015/09/19/charting-match-charting/</guid>
      <description>With the existence of Hawkeye and the IBM Slamtracker, tennis fans might be under the impression that the CPUs of tennis analysts are overflowing with high-quality stroke-by-stroke data on today&amp;rsquo;s matches. Regrettably, this is far from the truth. The data that drives the most interesting visualizations during a broadcasts, like summaries of the frequency of shots by their position on court, or the data behind the Challenge System are under the proprietary control of a few corporate giants (IBM for the Slams, SAP for the WTA), which means they are also out-of-reach of tennis researchers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Era of Efficiency for Roger Federer</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2015/09/13/roger-federer-new-era-efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2015/09/13/roger-federer-new-era-efficiency/</guid>
      <description>Today, Roger Federer will make his first appearance at a US Open final since 2009, where he lost to Juan Martin Del Potro. Since that match, Federer has reached the finals of 5 other Grand Slams but has not won a title since his 2012 victory at Wimbledon over Andy Murray. Following that title win, he has advanced to a final at two Slams, the 2014 and 2015 Wimbledon Championships; in each case, losing to Novak Djokovic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Did the US Open Rob Serena of a Calendar Slam?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2015/09/12/usopen-rob-serena/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2015/09/12/usopen-rob-serena/</guid>
      <description>Serena Williams&#39; loss to unseeded Roberta Vinci at the 2015 US Open semifinal put a shocking end to Williams&#39; run for a Calendar Slam. When Vinci stepped onto Ashe yesterday, the task before her must have seemed unthinkable. She had never won a set against Williams in their 4 previous meetings, and all of their prior matches were before the semifinal round, when Williams&#39; is known not to play at her highest level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Things You Won&#39;t Believe About IBM Insights!</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2015/09/10/ibm-insights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2015/09/10/ibm-insights/</guid>
      <description>At the 2015 US Open, IBM is continuing its long partnership with the USTA to bring tennis fans &amp;ldquo;more than the score&amp;rdquo;. One of the main ways that Big Blue is going beyond the score is with their Keys to the Match&amp;ndash;basically, a dashboard with performance targets for a given head-to-head.
If you are like me and have ever perused the Keys on a changeover over player bathroom break, you might have wondered exactly what insights they contain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Aging ATP - No End in Sight</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2015/09/06/atp-aging-no-end-in-sight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2015/09/06/atp-aging-no-end-in-sight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With Donald Young&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://espn.go.com/tennis/usopen15/story/_/id/13592494/us-open-donald-young-continues-string-dramatic-comebacks-open&#34;&gt;stunning comeback&lt;/a&gt; over Victor Troicki on Day 6 of the US Open, he became the youngest player to advance to the Round of 16&amp;ndash;making 26 the new young in tennis. The average age of the 16 men still in contention for the title is 29.3 years and 5 of the 16 [Feliciano Lopez (34.0), Jo-Wilfried Tsonga (30.4), Stan Wawrinka (30.4), John Isner (30.4), Roger Federer (34.1)] are over thirty.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WTA - Aging with Greatness</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2015/09/05/wta-aging-with-greatness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2015/09/05/wta-aging-with-greatness/</guid>
      <description>When Serena Williams turns 34 in a few weeks, she will very likely have added a 22nd Major title and Calendar Slam to her CV&amp;ndash;securing her reign as the most decorated thirty-and-over in the sport. A decade ago, few would have believed that a tennis player in her mid-thirties would be at the peak of her game. There&amp;rsquo;s no doubt that Williams&#39; achievements and resurgence at this stage in her career are exceptional.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retirements Aren&#39;t Only About Standing the Heat</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2015/09/04/atp-us-open-2015-retirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2015/09/04/atp-us-open-2015-retirements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Heat was the main topic of discussion on Day 4 of the US Open. The brutal effects of sweltering temperatures and stifling humidity took centerstage during the afternoon play when American Jack Sock collapsed in the third set of his match against Ruben Bemelmans. Sock&amp;ndash;who looked unconscious as the medical team on site rushed to his aid&amp;ndash;was forced to retire and was subsequently diagnosed with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/early-lead/wp/2015/09/03/american-tennis-player-jack-sock-collapses-on-court-at-u-s-open/&#34;&gt;heat illness&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WTA Early Upsets at 2015 US Open - Not Too Surprising</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2015/09/03/wta-us-open-2015-upsets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2015/09/03/wta-us-open-2015-upsets/</guid>
      <description>Day 4 of the 2015 US Open and the tournament has already brought a lot of surprises. While we all might have expected Nick Kyrgios to exit with flare in the first round, few of us would have anticipated that the first round would say farewell to so many of the seeds. The ladies&#39; draw feels especially bare after 11 of 32 seeds (34%) did not advance to the second round&amp;ndash;Stephens (29), Pavlyuchenkova (31), Pliskova (8), Kuznetsova (30), Suarez Navarro (10), Jankovic (21), Ivanovic (7), Safarova (6), Begu (28), Bacsinszky (14), Cornet (27).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>The sabermetric revolution popularized by Moneyball forever changed the way we experience and appreciate America&amp;rsquo;s pastime. Since then, more and more sports organisations have begun to see the value of statistical analysis and opened up positions for statisticians.
Over the past decade, statistical thinking in sport has begun to spread. And we can see the impact of analytics in the way it has reshaped recruitment, game style, and game experience for many of the most popular global sports.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/post/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/post/contact/</guid>
      <description>E-mail: s.a.kovalchik@gmail.com
Twitter: @StatsOnTheT</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Features</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/post/features/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/post/features/</guid>
      <description>Below is a selection of news features on my research.
  Stephanie Kovalchik (25 Jun 2019), The Conversation: How Ash Barty became the world&amp;rsquo;s best female tennis player
  Dean Evans (01 Nov 2018). Intel UK In Tennis, Big Data is Making a Grand Slam .
  Tennishead (23 Oct 2018). Hardest, fastest. New player analysis
  Preethi Ramamoorthy (05 May 2017), The Hindu: Tennis enters the matrix</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ratings</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/ratings/ratings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/ratings/ratings/</guid>
      <description>The links below provide singles and doubles ratings based on the Game Insight Group (GIG) player ratings. These are a margin of victory based Elo rating system that accounts not only for the win result but also the game margin (games won minus games lost). Ratings are based on matches played above the Futures/ITF level, including qualifying and main draw matches. Surface-adjusted ratings weight all-surface and surface-specific ratings according to the correlation of each with win results and the surface in question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/post/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/post/research/</guid>
      <description>Selected research. Full list can be found on Google Scholar.
  Kovalchik, S. A., &amp;amp; Ingram, M. (2018). Estimating the duration of professional tennis matches for varying formats. Journal of Quantitative Analysis in Sports, 14(1), 13-23.
  Kovalchik, S., &amp;amp; Reid, M. (2018). A shot taxonomy in the era of tracking data in professional tennis. Journal of Sports Sciences, 36(18), 2096-2104.
  Albert, J., &amp;amp; Kovalchik, S. (2017).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/post/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/post/software/</guid>
      <description>Software for tennis data scraping and analysis.
  R package deuce for accessing and wrangling with historical tennis data
  R package slam-sofascoreR for scraping Grand Slam data from Sofa Scorer
  Sports Analytics with R Tutorial
  All other code at github/skoval
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serena Williams’ Only Obstacle to a Calendar Slam is Herself</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2015/08/31/serena-williams-only-obstacle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2015/08/31/serena-williams-only-obstacle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a 21-minute opening match at the US Open that ended with her opponent&amp;rsquo;s retirement, Serena Williams is now 6 victories from her first Calendar Slam and 22nd career major title, tying her with Steffi Graf for the woman with the most Slam titles in the Open Era. Williams comes to Flushing Methods with a season match record of 48 wins to 2 losses—a record so close to perfection that you couldn’t blame her if she strutted onto Arthur Ashe and talked trash on a changeover or two (young Aussies, take note). But don’t expect Williams to rock swag until the Open trophy is sitting securely in her hands. As much as the wins keep coming, the queen of the court’s confidence has been in a perplexing slump.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/post/the-most-surprising-runs-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/post/the-most-surprising-runs-ever/</guid>
      <description>The most surprising runs of all time on the ATPDenis Shapovalov surprised the tennis world in Montreal by reaching the semi finals in stunning fashion, beating Del Potro and Nadal back-to-back. This made me wonder: was this one of the most surprising runs ever in tennis?To try to answer this question, I look at the likelihood of players&#39; runs under Elo. The likelihood is simply the probabilities of multiple events multiplied together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ATP Doubles Ratings</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/ratings/atp-doubles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/ratings/atp-doubles/</guid>
      <description> $(document).ready(function () { $(&#39;#atp-ratings&#39;).DataTable({ &#39;paging&#39;: false, &#39;pageLength&#39;: 1 }); });    player last_update overall hard grass clay     1 NIKOLA MEKTIC 2021-05-16 2332 2294 2331 2275   2 MATE PAVIC 2021-05-19 2266 2247 2277 2219   3 RAJEEV RAM 2021-05-16 2152 2118 2149 2106   4 MARCEL GRANOLLERS 2021-05-15 2150 2074 2102 2113   5 JOE SALISBURY 2021-05-16 2148 2115 2147 2099   6 HORACIO ZEBALLOS 2021-05-15 2143 2066 2093 2108   7 TIM PUETZ 2021-05-17 2129 2028 2059 2089   8 ANDREAS MIES 2020-11-19 2105 2033 1886 2146   9 JUAN-SEBASTIAN CABAL 2021-05-12 2088 2046 2072 2049   10 JURGEN MELZER 2020-11-22 2086 2034 1935 2073   11 ROBERT FARAH 2021-05-12 2084 2042 2067 2047   12 HORIA TECAU 2021-05-14 2069 2047 2071 2032   13 KEVIN KRAWIETZ 2021-05-14 2068 2008 2024 2048   14 ANDY MURRAY 2021-05-13 2066 2058 2101 1998   15 HUGO NYS 2021-05-17 2058 1943 1977 2014   16 MICHAEL VENUS 2021-05-15 2051 2049 2060 2034   17 SERGIY STAKHOVSKY 2021-05-08 2050 1985 2031 1983   18 NICOLAS MAHUT 2021-05-18 2046 2011 2033 2014   19 ANDREY RUBLEV 2021-05-05 2035 2014 2082 1926   20 PIERRE-HUGUES HERBERT 2021-05-18 2033 1993 2009 2010   21 KEN SKUPSKI 2021-05-18 2033 2016 2057 1968   22 FILIP POLASEK 2021-05-13 2033 2039 2072 1979   23 PABLO CARRENO-BUSTA 2021-04-19 2029 2022 2057 1972   24 WESLEY KOOLHOF 2021-05-14 2026 1971 1993 1996   25 NATHANIEL LAMMONS 2021-05-15 2023 1966 1993 1984   26 VASEK POSPISIL 2021-02-13 2013 1980 1985 2008   27 BRUNO SOARES 2021-05-10 2007 2019 2039 1973   28 IVAN DODIG 2021-05-13 2005 2019 2051 1952   29 MARCUS DANIELL 2021-05-13 1999 1965 1988 1965   30 JOHN PEERS 2021-05-15 1997 1995 2007 1978   31 PHILIPP OSWALD 2021-05-13 1997 1964 1975 1983   32 NOVAK DJOKOVIC 2021-02-05 1990 1942 1946 1880   33 TOMISLAV BRKIC 2021-05-19 1987 1982 2004 1951   34 GONZALO ESCOBAR 2021-05-13 1984 1980 2003 1947   35 ARIEL BEHAR 2021-05-13 1984 1979 2001 1949   36 DOMINIK KOEPFER 2021-04-28 1981 1975 2005 1934   37 MARC POLMANS 2021-05-14 1978 1892 1921 1940   38 NIKOLA CACIC 2021-05-19 1965 1855 1891 1917   39 KAREN KHACHANOV 2021-05-05 1964 1939 1983 1897   40 JACK SOCK 2021-04-17 1961 1931 1936 1956   41 ALEXANDER ZVEREV 2021-05-07 1959 1894 1948 1877   42 MARCELO AREVALO 2021-05-15 1958 1929 1952 1924   43 RAVEN KLAASEN 2021-05-18 1958 1902 1934 1911   44 SADIO DOUMBIA 2021-05-19 1956 1847 1876 1921   45 FELIPE MELIGENI RODRIGUES ALVES 2021-05-18 1954 1951 1965 1931   46 FABIEN REBOUL 2021-05-19 1952 1852 1879 1919   47 MATTEO BERRETTINI 2021-04-23 1948 1941 1977 1889   48 MATWE MIDDELKOOP 2021-05-15 1946 1909 1944 1893   49 DANIEL EVANS 2021-05-12 1946 1930 1973 1878   50 ANTOINE HOANG 2021-03-27 1945 1920 1924 1941   51 NEAL SKUPSKI 2021-05-18 1945 1990 2021 1889   52 BEN MCLACHLAN 2021-05-18 1941 1848 1885 1891   53 SANDER GILLE 2021-05-12 1940 1894 1922 1900   54 JORAN VLIEGEN 2021-05-12 1935 1888 1914 1898   55 SIMONE BOLELLI 2021-05-17 1934 1929 1953 1896   56 LUKASZ KUBOT 2021-05-13 1934 1905 1931 1894   57 JAN ZIELINSKI 2021-05-14 1931 1891 1920 1890   58 ALEKSANDR NEDOVESOV 2021-05-18 1930 1870 1894 1898   59 MARC-ANDREA HUESLER 2021-05-18 1928 1890 1954 1829   60 ASLAN KARATSEV 2021-03-12 1927 1906 1909 1923   61 JOHN ISNER 2021-03-29 1927 1901 1906 1923   62 STEVE JOHNSON 2021-05-18 1925 1893 1920 1885   63 SZYMON WALKOW 2021-05-18 1924 1879 1897 1899   64 BENJAMIN BONZI 2021-03-27 1922 1900 1904 1919   65 JEREMY CHARDY 2021-05-05 1920 1926 1942 1893   66 RYAN HARRISON 2021-01-13 1919 1880 1820 1910   67 SEM VERBEEK 2021-05-19 1916 1876 1917 1852   68 HUNTER REESE 2021-05-19 1915 1839 1860 1889   69 DENIS SHAPOVALOV 2021-05-10 1915 1909 1941 1865   70 ANDRE GORANSSON 2021-05-19 1914 1910 1930 1882   71 RAFAEL MATOS 2021-05-18 1913 1910 1927 1886   72 IVAN SABANOV 2021-05-12 1909 1820 1853 1865   73 MATEJ SABANOV 2021-05-12 1905 1817 1850 1862   74 JACK WITHROW 2021-05-15 1902 1874 1919 1831   75 FEDERICO DELBONIS 2021-03-14 1901 1898 1912 1879   76 KEVIN ANDERSON 2020-09-15 1901 1893 1858 1866   77 THANASI KOKKINAKIS 2021-02-14 1895 1890 1890 1894   78 ANDREY GOLUBEV 2021-05-18 1892 1838 1858 1865   79 NICK KYRGIOS 2021-02-14 1891 1857 1862 1885   80 FABIO FOGNINI 2021-05-13 1891 1885 1917 1839   81 REILLY OPELKA 2021-03-09 1888 1863 1867 1884   82 YANNICK HANFMANN 2021-04-28 1887 1886 1891 1877   83 CHRISTIAN HARRISON 2021-04-17 1887 1869 1872 1884   84 ANDREA VAVASSORI 2021-05-18 1887 1869 1888 1858   85 HENRI KONTINEN 2021-05-17 1886 1871 1889 1859   86 ANDRES MOLTENI 2021-05-17 1885 1881 1902 1853   87 EDOUARD ROGER-VASSELIN 2021-05-17 1883 1893 1905 1862   88 GUIDO ANDREOZZI 2021-05-05 1881 1878 1895 1853   89 MARIN CILIC 2021-05-18 1879 1856 1874 1852   90 LUKAS KLEIN 2021-03-27 1877 1869 1908 1815   91 MATTHEW EBDEN 2021-05-19 1876 1879 1906 1833   92 DANIIL MEDVEDEV 2021-05-13 1873 1866 1905 1810   93 DOMINIC INGLOT 2021-05-18 1873 1826 1857 1828   94 MAXIMO GONZALEZ 2021-05-17 1872 1878 1891 1849   95 NICOLAS JARRY 2021-03-11 1872 1873 1865 1885   96 CHRISTIAN GARIN 2021-05-12 1871 1867 1888 1838   97 MARCELO DEMOLINER 2021-05-19 1864 1845 1878 1813   98 FELIX AUGER ALIASSIME 2021-05-04 1862 1852 1935 1728   99 LUKAS ROSOL 2021-04-30 1862 1860 1868 1849   100 EVAN KING 2021-05-19 1861 1776 1803 1826    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ATP Singles Ratings</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/ratings/atp-singles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/ratings/atp-singles/</guid>
      <description> $(document).ready(function () { $(&#39;#atp-ratings&#39;).DataTable({ &#39;paging&#39;: false, &#39;pageLength&#39;: 1 }); });    player last_update overall hard grass clay     1 NOVAK DJOKOVIC 2021-05-16 2649 2641 2681 2586   2 RAFAEL NADAL 2021-05-16 2638 2636 2645 2624   3 STEFANOS TSITSIPAS 2021-05-15 2524 2457 2496 2468   4 ROGER FEDERER 2021-05-18 2479 2451 2484 2428   5 ALEXANDER ZVEREV 2021-05-14 2468 2411 2447 2416   6 DANIIL MEDVEDEV 2021-05-12 2462 2433 2567 2248   7 ANDREY RUBLEV 2021-05-15 2422 2393 2440 2349   8 MATTEO BERRETTINI 2021-05-13 2405 2398 2432 2350   9 DOMINIC THIEM 2021-05-13 2383 2352 2371 2355   10 JANNIK SINNER 2021-05-19 2373 2309 2377 2270   11 ASLAN KARATSEV 2021-05-19 2342 2294 2366 2231   12 CASPER RUUD 2021-05-19 2332 2222 2262 2279   13 PABLO CARRENO-BUSTA 2021-05-09 2329 2274 2304 2287   14 MILOS RAONIC 2021-03-30 2328 2301 2305 2324   15 ROBERTO BAUTISTA AGUT 2021-05-13 2321 2285 2329 2255   16 LORENZO SONEGO 2021-05-15 2309 2212 2252 2254   17 NICK KYRGIOS 2021-02-12 2260 2229 2234 2255   18 ALEJANDRO DAVIDOVICH FOKINA 2021-05-13 2260 2179 2238 2173   19 GRIGOR DIMITROV 2021-05-19 2250 2213 2250 2194   20 DIEGO SEBASTIAN SCHWARTZMAN 2021-05-11 2243 2205 2213 2235   21 JOHN ISNER 2021-05-07 2239 2185 2221 2186   22 DENIS SHAPOVALOV 2021-05-13 2237 2198 2251 2155   23 HUBERT HURKACZ 2021-05-04 2229 2204 2280 2109   24 ILYA IVASHKA 2021-05-19 2229 2153 2214 2139   25 BORNA CORIC 2021-03-06 2221 2197 2201 2217   26 DANIEL EVANS 2021-05-10 2220 2175 2255 2096   27 CHRISTIAN GARIN 2021-05-12 2219 2111 2148 2171   28 CAMERON NORRIE 2021-05-17 2219 2163 2228 2120   29 FEDERICO DELBONIS 2021-05-14 2216 2078 2111 2176   30 FELIX AUGER ALIASSIME 2021-05-18 2209 2182 2226 2140   31 MARTON FUCSOVICS 2021-05-19 2203 2191 2237 2130   32 STAN WAWRINKA 2021-03-09 2199 2173 2177 2194   33 KEI NISHIKORI 2021-05-13 2199 2165 2180 2178   34 VASEK POSPISIL 2021-03-24 2191 2170 2173 2187   35 ALBERT RAMOS-VINOLAS 2021-05-05 2186 2078 2113 2140   36 TAYLOR HARRY FRITZ 2021-05-11 2183 2151 2200 2107   37 GAEL MONFILS 2021-05-18 2179 2169 2218 2101   38 KAREN KHACHANOV 2021-05-19 2175 2156 2175 2147   39 ALEX DE MINAUR 2021-05-10 2168 2128 2235 1999   40 KEVIN ANDERSON 2021-04-28 2167 2137 2142 2163   41 LLOYD HARRIS 2021-05-10 2160 2131 2217 2024   42 DAVID GOFFIN 2021-05-19 2157 2123 2137 2138   43 ALEXANDER BUBLIK 2021-05-10 2150 2108 2183 2032   44 JO-WILFRIED TSONGA 2021-05-18 2139 2119 2139 2108   45 SEBASTIAN KORDA 2021-05-19 2139 2110 2193 2008   46 FRANCES TIAFOE 2021-05-08 2137 2120 2155 2083   47 FILIP KRAJINOVIC 2021-05-09 2133 2131 2147 2107   48 CARLOS ALCARAZ GARFIA 2021-05-19 2133 1997 2038 2079   49 MARCO CECCHINATO 2021-05-17 2132 2001 2044 2076   50 JAN-LENNARD STRUFF 2021-05-12 2121 2079 2102 2088   51 REILLY OPELKA 2021-05-18 2121 2079 2121 2058   52 TOMMY PAUL 2021-05-18 2119 2071 2107 2067   53 JEREMY CHARDY 2021-05-03 2117 2095 2139 2048   54 FABIO FOGNINI 2021-05-18 2113 2091 2113 2080   55 KYLE EDMUND 2020-10-24 2110 2067 1953 2103   56 ALEXEI POPYRIN 2021-05-08 2109 2082 2132 2030   57 TOMAS MACHAC 2021-03-07 2107 2075 2080 2102   58 PIERRE-HUGUES HERBERT 2021-05-17 2104 2082 2121 2043   59 LORENZO MUSETTI 2021-05-19 2104 2048 2091 2040   60 NIKOLOZ BASILASHVILI 2021-05-11 2102 2055 2070 2082   61 SEBASTIAN BAEZ 2021-05-15 2097 2095 2105 2082   62 GIANLUCA MAGER 2021-05-12 2094 2090 2113 2056   63 JAUME ANTONI MUNAR CLAR 2021-05-08 2087 2083 2105 2051   64 UGO HUMBERT 2021-05-17 2087 2068 2163 1934   65 ALJAZ BEDENE 2021-05-19 2086 2053 2083 2040   66 MACKENZIE MCDONALD 2021-05-17 2068 2039 2110 1956   67 LASLO DJERE 2021-05-18 2066 1978 1994 2048   68 MIOMIR KECMANOVIC 2021-05-10 2066 2035 2077 2002   69 PABLO ANDUJAR 2021-05-18 2065 2064 2071 2054   70 CORENTIN MOUTET 2021-05-17 2064 2055 2099 1993   71 PEDRO MARTINEZ PORTERO 2021-05-19 2063 2057 2085 2018   72 ANDY MURRAY 2021-03-03 2060 2046 2048 2058   73 MARIN CILIC 2021-05-18 2060 2035 2035 2062   74 EMIL RUUSUVUORI 2021-05-01 2059 2032 2139 1888   75 MARCOS GIRON 2021-05-08 2056 2026 2103 1933   76 STEFANO TRAVAGLIA 2021-05-12 2055 2015 2029 2038   77 EGOR GERASIMOV 2021-05-08 2055 2033 2105 1940   78 RICHARD GASQUET 2021-05-18 2054 2032 2063 2005   79 SOON-WOO KWON 2021-04-21 2051 1997 2107 1878   80 BERNABE ZAPATA MIRALLES 2021-05-18 2050 1972 1998 2016   81 FACUNDO BAGNIS 2021-05-19 2047 2045 2056 2029   82 JENSON BROOKSBY 2021-04-25 2046 1995 2091 1895   83 DOMINIK KOEPFER 2021-05-19 2034 1973 2007 1985   84 ARTHUR RINDERKNECH 2021-05-19 2032 1987 2047 1938   85 JOHN MILLMAN 2021-05-12 2029 1988 2018 1984   86 DANIEL ELAHI GALAN 2021-05-15 2028 1951 1978 1993   87 LUCAS POUILLE 2021-04-15 2027 1988 2000 2012   88 TALLON GRIEKSPOOR 2021-05-11 2027 1990 2021 1980   89 FRANCISCO CERUNDOLO 2021-04-20 2025 2024 2030 2015   90 TARO DANIEL 2021-05-19 2024 1974 2000 1988   91 PHILIPP KOHLSCHREIBER 2021-05-13 2022 2016 2044 1978   92 JUAN PABLO VARILLAS 2021-05-15 2020 2019 2025 2010   93 BJORN FRATANGELO 2021-05-17 2019 1993 2046 1936   94 PABLO CUEVAS 2021-05-18 2013 2011 2021 1996   95 KACPER ZUK 2021-05-12 2013 1943 1999 1930   96 YANNICK HANFMANN 2021-05-17 2011 1938 1950 2000   97 JEFF WOLF 2020-10-29 2010 1975 2107 1800   98 YOSHIHITO NISHIOKA 2021-05-17 2006 1970 2014 1939   99 JIRI VESELY 2021-05-18 2004 1976 2003 1963   100 KAMIL MAJCHRZAK 2021-05-19 2004 1999 2021 1968    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WTA Doubles Ratings</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/ratings/wta-doubles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/ratings/wta-doubles/</guid>
      <description> $(document).ready(function () { $(&#39;#wtaratings&#39;).DataTable({ &#39;paging&#39;: false, &#39;pageLength&#39;: 1 }); });    player last_update overall hard grass clay     1 KRISTINA MLADENOVIC 2021-05-16 2357 2342 2397 2302   2 BARBORA KREJCIKOVA 2021-05-14 2255 2182 2265 2201   3 CATY MCNALLY 2021-05-18 2255 2160 2273 2179   4 KATERINA SINIAKOVA 2021-05-14 2250 2176 2257 2199   5 ARYNA SABALENKA 2021-03-26 2250 2230 2240 2250   6 ASHLEIGH BARTY 2021-04-25 2225 2218 2243 2200   7 GIULIANA OLMOS 2021-05-16 2211 2120 2251 2111   8 TAYLOR TOWNSEND 2020-09-09 2209 2080 2073 2150   9 TIMEA BABOS 2021-05-19 2196 2177 2191 2190   10 DEMI SCHUURS 2021-05-13 2195 2137 2215 2139   11 SHARON FICHMAN 2021-05-16 2176 2156 2226 2107   12 CORI GAUFF 2021-05-18 2152 2076 2197 2056   13 NICOLE MELICHAR 2021-05-13 2144 2105 2164 2097   14 ELISE MERTENS 2021-05-13 2140 2115 2202 2054   15 VERONIKA KUDERMETOVA 2021-05-15 2138 2073 2150 2087   16 MARKETA VONDROUSOVA 2021-05-16 2119 2095 2179 2035   17 JENNIFER BRADY 2021-04-25 2116 2096 2167 2045   18 VICTORIA AZARENKA 2021-03-02 2104 2084 2094 2104   19 IGA SWIATEK 2021-05-04 2100 2028 2164 1983   20 KAROLINA PLISKOVA 2021-03-10 2100 2082 2091 2100   21 KVETA PESCHKE 2020-10-05 2099 2035 2084 2028   22 BARBORA STRYCOVA 2021-02-13 2098 2100 2099 2098   23 GARBINE MUGURUZA 2021-01-11 2094 2020 2021 2063   24 SANIA MIRZA 2021-03-10 2088 2074 2081 2088   25 NINA STOJANOVIC 2021-05-19 2082 2029 2110 2018   26 DARIJA JURAK 2021-05-19 2075 2057 2181 1940   27 ENA SHIBAHARA 2021-05-18 2071 2067 2146 1982   28 ALEXA GUARACHI 2021-05-19 2070 2055 2111 2013   29 SU-WEI HSIEH 2021-05-17 2068 2051 2109 2010   30 SHUKO AOYAMA 2021-05-18 2067 2066 2142 1979   31 ELENA VESNINA 2021-05-14 2055 2033 2078 2016   32 GABRIELA DABROWSKI 2021-05-18 2053 2012 2080 1997   33 JESSICA PEGULA 2021-05-11 2028 1999 2094 1934   34 VERA ZVONAREVA 2021-05-19 2028 1988 2047 1982   35 DESIRAE KRAWCZYK 2021-05-19 2010 1953 2014 1972   36 STORM SANDERS 2021-05-09 2009 1927 2001 1971   37 HAYLEY CARTER 2021-05-13 2008 2013 2057 1954   38 ASIA MUHAMMAD 2021-05-18 2007 1989 2058 1938   39 SIMONA HALEP 2021-03-26 1996 1966 1981 1996   40 ANASTASIA PAVLYUCHENKOVA 2021-05-07 1995 1897 1974 1962   41 DARIA GAVRILOVA 2021-02-11 1994 1936 1965 1994   42 LATISHA CHAN 2021-05-14 1990 1970 2040 1920   43 HAO-CHING CHAN 2021-05-14 1989 1968 2042 1916   44 LUISA STEFANI 2021-05-13 1989 1979 2024 1941   45 JELENA OSTAPENKO 2021-05-10 1988 1962 2021 1935   46 BETHANIE MATTEK-SANDS 2021-05-11 1988 1984 2047 1918   47 ALIZE CORNET 2021-02-06 1984 1876 1938 1894   48 MARTA KOSTYUK 2021-02-10 1976 1933 1954 1976   49 LAURA SIEGEMUND 2021-05-12 1973 1952 2027 1898   50 BELINDA BENCIC 2021-05-06 1965 1880 1969 1912   51 ANASTASIA POTAPOVA 2021-05-04 1963 1938 1998 1908   52 MARIE BOUZKOVA 2021-04-11 1956 1927 2031 1852   53 KATARZYNA KAWA 2021-05-01 1945 1856 1940 1899   54 KIKI BERTENS 2021-03-27 1944 1932 1938 1944   55 ANDREJA KLEPAC 2021-05-19 1940 1897 1965 1886   56 ANGELIQUE KERBER 2021-04-23 1938 1891 2011 1825   57 VIKTORIA KUZMOVA 2021-05-15 1937 1916 1965 1892   58 ELLEN PEREZ 2021-05-16 1931 1905 1975 1865   59 RALUCA OLARU 2021-05-10 1931 1892 1968 1866   60 JIL TEICHMANN 2021-05-06 1926 1905 1976 1854   61 SOFIA KENIN 2021-04-20 1922 1888 1981 1832   62 YIFAN XU 2021-05-18 1922 1927 1971 1869   63 NADIYA KICHENOK 2021-05-10 1921 1890 1980 1834   64 PETRA MARTIC 2021-05-11 1914 1846 1929 1855   65 LUCIE HRADECKA 2021-05-12 1913 1855 1902 1891   66 ZHAOXUAN YANG 2021-05-18 1909 1896 1972 1828   67 NAO HIBINO 2021-05-04 1906 1809 1905 1850   68 KRISTYNA PLISKOVA 2021-03-27 1900 1874 1887 1900   69 ASTRA SHARMA 2021-04-15 1892 1861 1944 1813   70 EKATERINE GORGODZE 2021-05-16 1884 1849 1908 1835   71 COCO VANDEWEGHE 2021-04-05 1883 1862 1920 1829   72 CHRISTINA MCHALE 2021-02-16 1882 1862 1872 1882   73 SHELBY ROGERS 2021-05-05 1877 1807 1875 1838   74 ONS JABEUR 2021-04-08 1876 1846 1953 1769   75 ALIAKSANDRA SASNOVICH 2021-05-07 1875 1826 1863 1861   76 MONICA NICULESCU 2021-05-12 1875 1860 1919 1815   77 SAISAI ZHENG 2021-05-12 1873 1838 1857 1871   78 OLGA DANILOVIC 2021-03-07 1872 1860 1866 1872   79 BERNARDA PERA 2021-02-15 1871 1823 1847 1871   80 YUKI NAITO 2021-04-10 1871 1845 1936 1780   81 BARBARA HAAS 2021-05-01 1870 1848 1924 1794   82 ANNA BLINKOVA 2021-03-26 1864 1845 1854 1864   83 EUGENIE BOUCHARD 2021-03-11 1861 1858 1860 1861   84 HARRIET DART 2021-04-29 1860 1851 1884 1827   85 MARTINA TREVISAN 2021-02-16 1857 1819 1838 1857   86 VALENTYNA IVAKHNENKO 2021-05-15 1855 1843 1885 1813   87 URSZULA RADWANSKA 2021-05-08 1853 1842 1883 1812   88 ANNA KALINSKAYA 2021-05-05 1852 1822 1881 1799   89 ALDILA SUTJIADI 2021-05-16 1849 1841 1869 1822   90 ANETT KONTAVEIT 2021-02-10 1848 1818 1833 1848   91 NADIA PODOROSKA 2021-05-11 1848 1842 1902 1781   92 ERI HOZUMI 2021-05-16 1847 1757 1803 1845   93 MAGDALENA FRECH 2021-04-30 1847 1791 1836 1828   94 MISAKI DOI 2021-05-17 1841 1835 1856 1820   95 CAROLINE DOLEHIDE 2021-05-14 1838 1834 1875 1793   96 ALISON RISKE 2021-02-11 1836 1817 1826 1836   97 MIYU KATO 2021-05-18 1835 1763 1822 1809   98 CAROLINE GARCIA 2021-05-16 1834 1866 1788 1907   99 SARA ERRANI 2021-05-15 1834 1825 1856 1803   100 SHUAI ZHANG 2021-05-18 1834 1794 1837 1807    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WTA Singles Ratings</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/ratings/wta-singles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/ratings/wta-singles/</guid>
      <description> $(document).ready(function () { $(&#39;#wta-ratings&#39;).DataTable({ &#39;paging&#39;: false, &#39;pageLength&#39;: 1 }); });    player last_update overall hard grass clay     1 ASHLEIGH BARTY 2021-05-13 2505 2448 2559 2409   2 ARYNA SABALENKA 2021-05-13 2470 2381 2542 2334   3 NAOMI OSAKA 2021-05-12 2455 2401 2593 2262   4 IGA SWIATEK 2021-05-16 2408 2304 2398 2358   5 GARBINE MUGURUZA 2021-05-13 2407 2363 2458 2322   6 SIMONA HALEP 2021-05-04 2387 2340 2412 2332   7 BIANCA VANESSA ANDREESCU 2021-04-01 2366 2345 2356 2366   8 VICTORIA AZARENKA 2021-04-30 2344 2295 2396 2254   9 SERENA WILLIAMS 2021-05-18 2330 2313 2372 2271   10 ELISE MERTENS 2021-05-11 2319 2286 2388 2220   11 JESSICA PEGULA 2021-05-14 2318 2237 2442 2126   12 KAROLINA MUCHOVA 2021-05-05 2314 2273 2417 2169   13 PETRA KVITOVA 2021-05-12 2314 2282 2369 2232   14 ELINA SVITOLINA 2021-05-15 2286 2241 2324 2216   15 MARIA SAKKARI 2021-05-12 2282 2242 2360 2168   16 JENNIFER BRADY 2021-05-10 2265 2202 2377 2098   17 VERONIKA KUDERMETOVA 2021-05-13 2259 2186 2288 2183   18 CORI GAUFF 2021-05-19 2246 2147 2296 2130   19 ONS JABEUR 2021-05-01 2239 2178 2281 2155   20 DANIELLE ROSE COLLINS 2021-03-25 2215 2181 2198 2215   21 ANETT KONTAVEIT 2021-05-02 2214 2182 2279 2121   22 PAULA BADOSA GIBERT 2021-05-18 2209 2088 2185 2167   23 KAROLINA PLISKOVA 2021-05-16 2209 2161 2218 2170   24 EKATERINA ALEXANDROVA 2021-05-13 2190 2114 2262 2062   25 BARBORA KREJCIKOVA 2021-05-13 2189 2140 2227 2116   26 DARIA KASATKINA 2021-05-18 2178 2144 2244 2081   27 SARA SORRIBES TORMO 2021-05-17 2166 2124 2211 2090   28 ANN LI 2021-03-20 2160 2144 2152 2160   29 AMANDA ANISIMOVA 2021-05-18 2158 2100 2182 2096   30 SHELBY ROGERS 2021-05-10 2157 2108 2267 2000   31 ANASTASIA PAVLYUCHENKOVA 2021-05-06 2156 2088 2192 2074   32 JELENA OSTAPENKO 2021-05-14 2144 2085 2170 2080   33 SORANA CIRSTEA 2021-04-30 2142 2063 2200 2029   34 VERA ZVONAREVA 2021-05-13 2141 2078 2172 2069   35 ELENA RYBAKINA 2021-05-02 2130 2082 2172 2053   36 KIKI BERTENS 2021-05-01 2110 2102 2116 2098   37 JULIA GOERGES 2020-10-01 2107 2041 2090 2041   38 FIONA FERRO 2021-04-22 2105 2016 2076 2087   39 IRINA-CAMELIA BEGU 2021-05-08 2101 2053 2118 2052   40 ANASTASIJA SEVASTOVA 2021-05-12 2097 2042 2108 2052   41 MADISON KEYS 2021-05-12 2093 2089 2130 2048   42 SOFIA KENIN 2021-05-12 2091 2064 2145 2012   43 MARTA KOSTYUK 2021-05-10 2088 2043 2127 2016   44 LAURA SIEGEMUND 2021-05-11 2085 2038 2100 2039   45 PETRA MARTIC 2021-05-19 2080 2026 2078 2051   46 AJLA TOMLJANOVIC 2021-05-18 2074 2014 2100 2008   47 JIL TEICHMANN 2021-05-10 2069 2030 2100 2010   48 TAMARA ZIDANSEK 2021-05-11 2065 1973 2045 2035   49 KAIA KANEPI 2021-05-18 2065 2037 2108 1999   50 ANGELIQUE KERBER 2021-05-13 2061 2026 2068 2032   51 YULIA PUTINTSEVA 2021-05-19 2058 2025 2081 2012   52 JOHANNA KONTA 2021-05-11 2057 2036 2066 2034   53 MARKETA VONDROUSOVA 2021-05-11 2055 2035 2068 2028   54 LEYLAH ANNIE FERNANDEZ 2021-05-17 2047 1995 2133 1916   55 CAROLINE GARCIA 2021-05-19 2045 1999 2046 2016   56 MARIE BOUZKOVA 2021-04-21 2045 1990 2140 1903   57 DAYANA YASTREMSKA 2020-11-09 2045 1991 1963 2042   58 VIKTORIJA GOLUBIC 2021-05-18 2044 2003 2096 1960   59 NADIA PODOROSKA 2021-05-18 2039 1959 2017 2018   60 BELINDA BENCIC 2021-05-11 2035 2023 2085 1970   61 KATERINA SINIAKOVA 2021-05-18 2034 1965 2021 2008   62 SVETLANA KUZNETSOVA 2021-03-24 2032 2020 2026 2032   63 TSVETANA PIRONKOVA 2021-04-27 2023 2000 2081 1942   64 BERNARDA PERA 2021-05-17 2022 1956 2015 1993   65 DONNA VEKIC 2021-02-15 2019 2008 2014 2019   66 CLARA TAUSON 2021-05-17 2014 1975 2080 1914   67 ANA KONJUH 2021-05-19 2006 1947 2014 1962   68 ALIAKSANDRA SASNOVICH 2021-05-19 2004 1961 2032 1947   69 ALISON RISKE 2021-04-29 2002 1968 2088 1882   70 CATHERINE CARTAN BELLIS 2020-11-05 1996 1911 1921 1951   71 DANKA KOVINIC 2021-05-17 1993 1900 1980 1955   72 KATIE BOULTER 2021-04-30 1992 1915 2063 1865   73 CLAIRE LIU 2021-05-09 1991 1873 1964 1953   74 ALIZE CORNET 2021-05-11 1986 1958 2015 1935   75 ANNA SCHMIEDLOVA 2021-05-18 1985 1931 1992 1945   76 SLOANE STEPHENS 2021-05-18 1984 1918 1956 1978   77 ELENA VESNINA 2021-05-08 1981 1965 2021 1925   78 LESYA TSURENKO 2021-03-16 1980 1956 1968 1980   79 CAMILA GIORGI 2021-05-19 1979 1940 1991 1942   80 EUGENIE BOUCHARD 2021-03-16 1972 1930 1951 1972   81 ANA BOGDAN 2021-05-18 1972 1922 1998 1912   82 BEATRIZ HADDAD MAIA 2021-05-14 1970 1956 2005 1922   83 DARIA GAVRILOVA 2021-02-11 1968 1957 1962 1968   84 ANNA KALINSKAYA 2021-05-18 1967 1926 2010 1893   85 MARIA CAMILA OSORIO SERRANO 2021-05-17 1965 1863 1966 1905   86 ZARINA DIYAS 2021-04-28 1962 1940 2018 1884   87 ANASTASIA POTAPOVA 2021-05-09 1960 1946 2001 1904   88 LIUDMILA SAMSONOVA 2021-05-19 1959 1934 2018 1877   89 ANDREA PETKOVIC 2021-05-16 1958 1928 2005 1885   90 TEREZA MARTINCOVA 2021-05-18 1950 1934 2012 1869   91 ASTRA SHARMA 2021-04-18 1948 1879 1976 1876   92 MAGDA LINETTE 2021-05-10 1947 1918 2023 1842   93 POLONA HERCOG 2021-05-17 1946 1912 1966 1904   94 HARMONY TAN 2021-05-08 1944 1919 2006 1857   95 LAUREN DAVIS 2021-04-14 1942 1890 1949 1904   96 SAISAI ZHENG 2021-05-11 1936 1895 1974 1868   97 MAGDALENA FRECH 2021-05-14 1935 1888 1952 1888   98 KAMILLA RAKHIMOVA 2021-05-18 1934 1854 1948 1871   99 QIANG WANG 2021-05-19 1932 1892 1953 1883   100 CLARA BUREL 2021-05-16 1929 1913 1970 1872    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
