<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>return impact on Stats On the T</title>
    <link>https://skoval.github.io/tags/return-impact/</link>
    <description>Recent content in return impact on Stats On the T</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://skoval.github.io/tags/return-impact/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Return Impact Head-to-Heads</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2021/04/17/Return-Impact-H2H/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2021/04/17/Return-Impact-H2H/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Head-to-heads are one of the most fascinating aspects of tennis. While it&amp;rsquo;s easy to look up who is ahead on one record or another, there are still many fundamental patterns of play that we can&amp;rsquo;t easily compare across players. This post goes a small (but I hope interesting) way towards remedying that by introducing a head-to-head visualization tool for comparing the return impact patterns of ATP players.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hardcourt First Return Impact Styles</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2021/01/23/Hardcourt-Return-Impact-Styles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2021/01/23/Hardcourt-Return-Impact-Styles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once we can measure player impact patterns on the return, it is natural to use these patterns to compare players. This post delves into these comparisons and presents a set of distinct impact types that describe the impact styles of top ATP players when returning the first serve on hardcourts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Return Impact Maps</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2021/01/19/Return-Impact-Maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2021/01/19/Return-Impact-Maps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Which of the top ATP players are the most aggressive on the serve return? Which are the most defensive? Is Andrey Rublev&amp;rsquo;s serve return style closer to Roger Federer&amp;rsquo;s or Novak Djokovic&amp;rsquo;s? In this post, I introduce an interactive visualization tool to help answer these and many other questions about the return impact of top men&amp;rsquo;s tennis players.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Foray Into Return Impact Patterns</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2020/11/28/Return-Impact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2020/11/28/Return-Impact/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The serve return is the most important shot for a receiver.  What can receivers do to put themselves in a better position to make a good impact on the serve return? The answer to that question is too big a task for one blog post alone. As a small first step, I take a look at a new public data source that includes the position of players at the time of return impact in ATP matches. Through a handful of case studies, it delves into the kind of patterns in return positioning these data could help reveal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
