<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>watchability on Stats On the T</title>
    <link>https://skoval.github.io/tags/watchability/</link>
    <description>Recent content in watchability on Stats On the T</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://skoval.github.io/tags/watchability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Men&#39;s US Open Watchability Ratings</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2022/08/27/Men&#39;s-US-Open-Watchability-Ratings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2022/08/27/Men&#39;s-US-Open-Watchability-Ratings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With Novak Djokovic officially out of the draw and Rafael Nadal playing with a chronic foot injury, the US Open is going to be a huge opportunity for each competitor looking for their first slam title. Here is a ratings-based ranking of the matches that could be the toughest and most watchable in the first two rounds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women&#39;s US Open Watchability Ratings</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2022/08/27/Women&#39;s-US-Open-Watchability-Ratings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2022/08/27/Women&#39;s-US-Open-Watchability-Ratings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the 2022 US Open set to be Serena Williams&amp;rsquo;s farewell event, all attention will be on the GOAT and the coda she ends her career with. If Williams does want to get into the second week, it is going to be a real challenge given the difficulty of her draw. And if the Wilson balls are flying as unusually this year as last, it could be another wild two weeks at Flushing Meadows. Here are some guesses at the matches that could be the toughest and most watchable in the first two rounds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Men&#39;s Wimbledon Watchability Ratings</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2022/06/25/Men&#39;s-Wimbledon-Watchability-Ratings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2022/06/25/Men&#39;s-Wimbledon-Watchability-Ratings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2022 Wimbledon Championships could be one of the more controversial years for the storied event, with Russian and Belarusian players unable to compete. But with Nadal committing to another Grand Slam venture this year and Djokovic awaiting him on the other side of the draw, it is not likely to be long before politics is replaced with the simple fascination with who will win. And here are the watchability stats for the first two rounds of the men&amp;rsquo;s draw.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Women&#39;s Wimbledon Watchability Ratings</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2022/06/25/Women&#39;s-Wimbledon-Watchability-Ratings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2022/06/25/Women&#39;s-Wimbledon-Watchability-Ratings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even with all the storylines swirling around the 2022 Wimbledon Championships, Serena Williams has managed to top the headlines with her decision to return to SW19 after more than a year from competition. All eyes will be on Williams, the true wildcard of the draw, as she makes her way towards the title. Here are some of the other most watchable contenders for the first week.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roland Garros Men&#39;s Watchability Ratings</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2022/05/20/Roland-Garros-Men&#39;s-Watchability-Ratings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2022/05/20/Roland-Garros-Men&#39;s-Watchability-Ratings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The draws are out for the 2022 edition of Roland Garros. With Rafael Nadal&amp;rsquo;s drought in clay Masters titles this season, it has been one of the more surprising lead ups to the clay slam in over a decade. With the skyrocketing success of Carlos Alcaraz, signs that Novak Djokovic is returning to form, and Nadal&amp;rsquo;s fitness up in the air; the stage is set for a thrilling fight for the French Open men&amp;rsquo;s title. Which matches are more likely to deliver the most thrills in the first rounds?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roland Garros Women&#39;s Watchability Ratings</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2022/05/20/Roland-Garros-Women&#39;s-Watchability-Ratings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2022/05/20/Roland-Garros-Women&#39;s-Watchability-Ratings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since Ash Barty&amp;rsquo;s retirement following her win at the Australian Open, Iga Swiatek has become the dominant force on the WTA tour. The French Open during Rafa&amp;rsquo;s reign has been a foregone conclusion in most years. But this year, it&amp;rsquo;s Swiatek who is the heaviest favorite at the event. The main question is which among her challengers can make this a more competitive event than expected? And before we know who might be fighting for the title, which womens matches are likely to be the must-sees of the first rounds?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ATP Rome Watchability Ratings</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2022/05/08/ATP-Rome-Watchability-Ratings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2022/05/08/ATP-Rome-Watchability-Ratings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are heading into the final Masters event of the clay swing in Rome. Will this be a redemption week for Djokovic and Nadal? Or can Alcaraz continue his fairy tale run? And before we learn the answers to those questions, what should we make sure to watch in the first days?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ATP Mutua Madrid Watchability Ratings</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2022/04/30/ATP-Mutua-Madrid-Watchability-Ratings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2022/04/30/ATP-Mutua-Madrid-Watchability-Ratings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the final weeks of the clay court circuit. Madrid will be the next big event on the men&amp;rsquo;s calendar and the first event of the year to feature Nadal and Djokovic. If Nadal and Djokovic were to meet, it would be a must-see match. But what about the matches in the early rounds? Which are likely to be the most exciting to watch?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
