<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pressure on Stats On the T</title>
    <link>https://skoval.github.io/tags/pressure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pressure on Stats On the T</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://skoval.github.io/tags/pressure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Felt the Pressure the Most at the 2019 Grand Slams?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/11/08/pressure-stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/11/08/pressure-stats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the Grand Slam calendar for 2019 now at a close, which players faced the greatest challenges at the majors? And which achieved the most under extreme pressure?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Were the Top Pressure Performers at the 2019 Grand Slams?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/11/15/pressure-win-stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/11/15/pressure-win-stats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I looked the the players who faced the most pressure at the Grand Slams in 2019. In this post, I ask the next obvious question. Who performed the best under high pressure?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Medvedev and Berrettini Dealt with Pressure at the US Open</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/09/13/us-open-pressure/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/09/13/us-open-pressure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The performances of Daniil Medvedev and Matteo Berrettini at the 2019 US Open showed that the future of men&amp;rsquo;s tennis is bright. In this post, I look at the point-by-point pressure each of these young stars had to confront and analyze how well they responded to it in each round of their US Open journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top Pressure Performances in March</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/03/29/top-pressure-performances/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/03/29/top-pressure-performances/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ahead of the final matches in Miami this weekend, we look back on the players who triumphed in the face of the most pressure-filled matches so far this month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Men&#39;s Top Pressure Performances in February</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/03/01/atp-bpe-feb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/03/01/atp-bpe-feb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the close of the second month of the 2019 season, we look back at the biggest pressure performances of the men&amp;rsquo;s tour. Reilley Opelka takes top honours for having faced the most service pressure in a match in February, racking up 15.5 break point equivalents (BPEs) against John Isner in New York. Opelka also saved the most of the BPEs faces winning a whopping 92% of high-pressure service points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Best Quantify Service Pressure</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2019/01/29/break-point-units/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2019/01/29/break-point-units/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pressure is one of those concepts in tennis that we all know exists but we struggle to calculate. I&amp;rsquo;ve made multiple attempts at quantifying scoreboard pressure and have yet to come around to one that is both statistically useful and easy to interpret. But some recent experimenting has uncovered what I think could be as close to a &amp;lsquo;best&amp;rsquo; statistic for pressure as I am likely to find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Has Experienced the Most and Least Set Pressure this Season?</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/11/17/experienced-pressure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/11/17/experienced-pressure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After introducing &lt;em&gt;Pressure Ratings&lt;/em&gt; for matches, this post looks at how a similar approach can be used to develop a &lt;em&gt;Set Competitiveness&lt;/em&gt; rating for players. The &lt;em&gt;Set Competitiveness&lt;/em&gt; measures the pressure of a player&amp;rsquo;s sets in a way that allows direct ranking against the pressure typically faced by other players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Pressure Ratings to Rank Most Competitive Matches in 2018</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2018/11/09/match-pressure-ratings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2018/11/09/match-pressure-ratings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week&amp;rsquo;s 252-point Paris Masters semifinal between Novak Djokovic and Roger Federer got many wondering whether it was the best match in their 47 match long rivalry. In this post, I introduce a pressure rating for sets and matches that can help to tell us to rate their relative competitiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessing Scoreboard Effects</title>
      <link>https://skoval.github.io/2017/10/06/scoreboard-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://skoval.github.io/2017/10/06/scoreboard-effects/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do the numbers on the scoreboard affect how a player performs? In this post, we look at how to measure scoreboard effects and identify some top players who appear vulnerable and others who seem impervious to the scoreboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>